演讲者1：好的 欢迎来到GD 50 第7讲
SPEAKER 1: All right, welcome to GD 50, lecture 7.
这周我们将谈论我最喜欢的特许经营权之一
This week we'll be talking about one of my favorite franchises of all time,
我童年的核心部分
a core part of my childhood--
口袋妖怪 就像屏幕上的口袋妖怪球一样
Pokemon as shown by the Poke Ball on the screen there.
我记得是在1997年 第一个口袋妖怪
So back in 1997 I think it was, the first Pokemon
游戏名称：红与蓝
game was released, Red and Blue.
我相信它是一年前在日本发布的
I believe it was released a year earlier in Japan where it
以红蓝绿三种颜色发布
was released as Red, Blue, and Green.
游戏的总体目标相当简单
And the overall goal of the game was fairly straightforward.
你是个宠物小精灵训练师
You were a Pokemon trainer.
你的目标是走进这个世界
Your goal was to go out into the world and try and capture
151种不同的生物
any number of 151 different types of these creatures called
口袋妖怪是基于一大堆不同类型的生物
Pokemon that were based on a whole bunch of different types of creatures.
在这里的截图显示 有一个Weepinbell战斗和Geodude
Shown in the screenshot here, there's a Weepinbell fighting and Geodude.
Geodude是岩石类型 Weepinbeel是草类型
A Geodude was a rock type, Weepinbeel was a grass type.
你有不同类型的口袋妖怪
You had different types of Pokemon.
当他们互相争斗的时候 有些人比其他人更好
When they fight each other, some types were better than other types,
就像是石头剪子布的关系
like this sort of very large rock, paper, scissors relationship.
这是一个非常上瘾的公式
And it was just a very addicting formula.
你会有一队这样的生物 你抓来养大的
You'd have a team of these creatures that you had caught and raised
和其他驯兽师战斗
and battled, and you'd fight other trainers.
最棒的是你可以
And the awesome part of this was you could go
你可以和你的朋友打架
and you could actually fight your friends,
或者和你抓到的朋友交换口袋妖怪
or trade Pokemon with your friends that they had caught.
你们经常互相分享故事
And you would often share stories back and forth
你可能会遇到的各种稀有生物
about the different rare creatures that you would have encountered,
以及各种各样的东西
and all sorts of things.
你会有一个定制的派对那是你的一部分
You'd have a customized party that was sort of a part of you.
这就是Pokemon Red
And so this is Pokemon Red.
该系列随着时间的推移而发展
The series has evolved over time.
这是几年前发布的《黄金与白银》的截图
This is a screenshot of Gold and Silver, which was released a couple of years
游戏机颜色Gameboy Color
afterwards for the Gameboy Color.
再次 这是为常规Gameboy发布的
Again, this was released for the regular Gameboy.
金银引入了一系列新功能 包括育种
Gold and Silver introduced a bunch of new features including breeding,
昼夜循环 还有很多其他的东西
and a day, night cycle, and a lot of other things
这成为了核心系列的一部分
that became part of the core series.
这是Ruby和Sapphire 这是为了《游戏男孩》而准备的
Here is Ruby and Sapphire, which was for the Gameboy Advance
得到了一个重要的图形更新 但核心公式
and got a significant graphical update, but the core formula
基本保持不变
stayed much the same.
这是钻石和珍珠 这是给DS的
Here is Diamond and Pearl, which is for the DS, which
它使用了两个屏幕 如上面和下面所示
it made use of two screens, as seen on the top and bottom there.
这是黑与白 这是又向前迈进了一步
Here is Black and White, which was another step forward
因为它为世界各地引入了三维图形
in that it introduced three dimensional graphics for the over world,
因此 你可以在该系列中第一次看到某种3D效果
so you could actually see some sort of 3D for the first time in the franchise.
最近 我们看到了像X和Y这样的3DS游戏
And then more recently, we've seen for the 3DS, games like X and Y,
如图所示 欧米茄蓝宝石 阿尔法红宝石--
which is shown here, and Omega Sapphire, Alpha Ruby--
阿尔法蓝宝石和欧米茄红宝石 以及月亮和太阳
Alpha Sapphire and Omega Ruby, and Moon and Sun.
这是一个很好的例子 说明了为什么
And so this is a great illustration of why
RPG类型的电子游戏 角色扮演游戏
the RPG genre of video games, role playing game,
尽管它在某种程度上是对这个公式的独特看法
even though it's sort of its own unique take on the formula.
但它允许我们 我们可以某种程度上剖析这个 并看看
But it allows us to, we can sort of dissect this and take a look
RPG是什么 口袋妖怪游戏又是什么
at what makes an RPG and what makes a Pokemon game altogether
做一个很酷的演示
for a nice cool demonstration.
因此 今天 我们将谈论一些新事物
So today, we'll be talking about a few new things.
在这个讲课示例中 我们的做法会有很大不同
We'll be doing things a lot differently in this lecture example
相对于其他例子 因为我们正在从国家过渡
relative to other examples, because we're transitioning away from the state
机器 并谈论一种称为状态堆栈的结构 该结构
machine and talking about a construct called the state stack, which
实际上是状态机的更高级版本
is effectively a more advanced version of the state machine.
而在此之前 我们有一个状态机 它一次处于一个状态
Whereas before, we had a state machine that was in one state at a time,
因此 我们可能处于播放状态或开始状态或其他状态
whereby we could be in the play state or the start state or what
不 我们现在实际上可以有多个州
not, we can now actually have multiple states
它们并行地存在于一堆数据结构上 您已经
that exist in parallel that are on a stack of data structure, which you've
在CS 50中可以看到 如果你已经采取了 我们可以有
seen in CS 50 if you've taken, where we can have,
例如 场状态、最底部的播放状态、
for example, the field state, the play state at the very bottom,
它总是在那里 然后我们可以将状态推送到堆栈上
which is always there, and then we can push states onto the stack
正如我们所需要的 例如 对话状态
as we need to for example, a dialog state
这样我们就可以实际显示一些对话框
so that we can actually display some dialog,
将一些文本放到屏幕上 而不是摆脱播放状态
some text to the screen without getting rid of the play state
我们以前在那里吃过的
that we had there before.
它允许我们同时渲染多个物体
It allows us to render multiple things at the same time,
然后也返回到先前的状态
and then also return back to prior states,
而不是每次都完全创建新的状态
rather than completely create new states every time
我们想要做一个转变
we want to make a transition.
我们将讨论基于转弯的系统
We'll be talking about turn based systems.
所以像精灵宝可梦和其他RPG一样 在那里
So an RPGs like Pokemon and others, there
通常是战斗系统 通常是
are often battle systems that are usually
在你打斗的这一特定类型中转身--你有
turn based in this particular genre where you're fighting-- you have
一支球队或一个角色与另一支球队或另一支球队或另一支球队作战
one team or one character fighting against against one other team or one
其他角色 你们轮流打架
other character, and you take turns fighting each other.
你有无限的时间来做决定
And you have an indefinite amount of time to make your decision
然后形成某种战略 关于如何
and then form some sort of strategy as to how
你想要解决这个问题
you want to approach the problem.
我们将看到一个非常原始的基于转弯的系统
We'll be taking a look at a very primitive turn based system,
但今天是一个功能齐全的系统
but a fully functional one today.
这一类型的另一个重要方面是图形用户界面或图形用户界面
Another huge aspect of this genre is graphical user interfaces or GUIs
因为它们被缩短了
as they're shortened.
面板、滚动条、文本框和菜单等
Things like panels, and scroll bars, and text boxes, and menus, all
这类东西让我们可以更直观地看到
sorts of these things that allow us to get a more visual sort of look
并使我们能够更好地驾驭更复杂的游戏生态系统
at our data, and allow us to navigate a much more complex game ecosystem more
效率很高
efficiently.
为了把这一切联系在一起 RPG的机械师
And to tie it all together, RPG mechanics at large,
我们将考虑升级和体验等内容
we'll be looking at things like leveling up and experience
以及如何计算一方对另一方造成的损害
and how to calculate the damage that one party does to the other party
在战斗的整个过程中
throughout the course of a battle.
因此 这将是一组相当复杂的例子
And so it will be a fairly complicated set of examples,
但作为一个整体 它相当说明了这一流派
but fairly illustrative of the genre as a whole.
所以我想演示一下我放在一起的例子
So I'd like to demonstrate sort of the example that I put together.
如果我能从观众中找个志愿者过来看看的话
If I could get a volunteer from the audience to come up and take a look.
托尼 那太棒了 太感谢你了
Tony that'd be awesome, thank you so much.
这就是我简单但功能齐全的精灵宝可梦的演示
So this is my simple but fully featured, more or less, demonstration of Pokemon.
所以如果你想进入或返回
So if you want to enter or return.
所以这是一个
So this is a--
所以这里我们有一个
so here we have a--
我们可以马上看到 我们有一个文本框和一个播放状态
we can see right off the bat, we have a text box and a play state
就像我们以前那样
like we did before.
所以这个文本框实际上是一个在地方之上的状态
So this text box is actually a state that's layered above the place.
所以你可以看到它有一些说明 如果你想按P
So you can see it has some instructions about, if you want to press P,
你可以治愈你的口袋妖怪
you can heal your Pokemon.
您可以按Enter键取消
You can press Enter to dismiss.
如果你继续按回车键
So if you go ahead and press Enter, you'll
现在能够真正移动了
be able to actually move around now.
需要注意的是 输入实际上
And so something to note is before, input was actually
当对话在屏幕顶部时停止播放状态
halted while the dialogue was on the top of the screen for the play state.
你实际上不允许访问或更新这个底部状态
You're actually not allowed to access or update this bottom state,
因为状态堆栈只允许输入到顶部状态
because the state stack is only allowing input to the top state.
所以我把这个游戏限制在这个盒子里
And so I have limited the play here just to this box,
但如果我们在这里的高草中行走 在口袋妖怪里
but if we walk in the tall grass down here, in Pokemon,
为了真正开始一次邂逅
in order to actually initiate an encounter
与另一个口袋妖怪或另一个野生口袋妖怪 你走在草地上
with another Pokemon or another wild Pokemon, you walk in the grass.
我们在草地上走了一圈
So here we've walked in the grass.
这种情况发生的概率是随机的 有十分之一的概率
There's a random chance for this to happen, there's a 1 in 10 chance
基本上
basically.
原来是说有野竹子出现了
So it's saying that a wild Bamboon appeared.
一个野生动物出现了
So a wild creature appeared.
他是5级 我们是5级 应该是一个相当公平的战斗
He's level 5, we're level 5, should be a fairly even battle.
你可以按回车键 它会说开始
So you can press Enter, and it will say go
你的口袋妖怪的名字 在这个例子中是一个Aardart
the name of your Pokemon, which is an Aardart in this case,
现在是随机分配的
and it's randomly allocated at the moment.
所以再按一次回车键
So go ahead and press Enter one more time.
现在我们可以看到右下角 我们有一个菜单
Now we can see on the bottom right, we have a menu.
所以我们要么战斗要么逃跑 这两个选择
So we can fight or we can run, so those two choices.
所以我们可以继续战斗
So we can go ahead and fight.
所以我们战斗 谁的口袋妖怪更高
So we fight, whichever Pokemon has the higher
速度是第一位的 会造成伤害
speed will go first and do damage.
很明显 我们造成的伤害更大 但他的速度更快
We obviously, do a lot more damage, but he's a little bit faster,
所以他会先来
so he's going to go first.
所以我们再打一次
So we fight one more time.
我们应该能把他打晕
We should be able to knock him out.
所以一旦我们这样做了 我们就得到了胜利的信息 我们得到了胜利的歌曲
So as soon as we do, we get a victory message, we get a victory song.
如果我们按下回车键
If we press Enter, we'll actually get some experience
因为打败了那个敌人
for defeating that enemy.
所以我们有相当多的经验 我们有65个XP
So we've got quite a bit of experience, we got 65 XP.
在底部栏中 我们可以看到我们有所有这些图形用户界面元素
In that bottom bar, we can see we have all these GUI elements,
我们这里有一个面板 我们有文本框 我们有进度条
we've got a panel here, we have text boxes, we have progress bars,
所有这些部分结合在一起 给了我们某种基于回合的系统
all these pieces are coming together to give us sort of this turn based system.
所以在这之后 我们可能会升级 只是为了演示
And so after this, we may level up just to demonstrate
水平 这是这个游戏的RPG机械学的一部分
leveling, which is part of the RPG mechanic side of this game.
所以我们必须再按一次
So we have to press this one more time.
我们做到了 非常完美
We did, perfectly.
所以他们升级了
So they leveled up.
现在我们是级别6 所以我们可以看到进度条上方的6发生了变化
And so now we're level 6, so we can see the 6 changed above our progress bars.
因此 现在每次都会变得更强大
So now will be a little bit stronger every time.
统计数据没有在这里显示 这实际上是作业的一部分
And the stats aren't shown here, it's actually a part of the assignment
是创建一个菜单 它将实际显示您是如何升级的
is to create a menu that will actually show you how you leveled up,
实际增加的统计数据
what stats actually increased.
但在引擎盖下 在幕后
But underneath the hood, behind the scenes,
你实际上得到了统计数据的增长
you actually are getting stat increases.
所以在这里我们可以看到 如果我们的HP一直降到零
And so here we can see that if we our HP goes all the way down to zero,
我们晕倒了
we faint.
当我们昏倒时 屏幕不是褪色为白色
And when we faint, the screen instead of fading to white
实际上会褪色为黑色 以说明区别
will actually fade to black to illustrate the difference
在这两个转变之间
between the two transitions.
这样我们就可以无限期地玩下去
And so that we can keep playing indefinitely,
这个游戏会让你的精灵宝可梦完全恢复健康
the game will restore your Pokemon back to full health.
因此 这将永远持续下去
And so this will go on forever.
这实际上就是模拟器 它只是
This is effectively what the simulator is, it's just
一系列简单的无休止的战斗
a simple series of infinite battles.
草丛中有随机的精灵宝可梦
There are random Pokemon in the grass.
你总共可以打五场比赛
There's five total that you can fight.
但构成这款游戏的所有核心要素都在这里
But all the core pieces of what make the game are here.
所以实际上 让我们也来演示一下跑步
So actually, let's illustrate running too
如果您不介意的话 让我们看看有没有什么不同
if you wouldn't mind, just so that we can see if there is a difference.
所以我们真的可以逃走 然后在战斗中我们会在那里被切断
So we can actually flee, and then battle we'll get cut short there.
我们不会得到任何XP 我们不会晕倒 但我们仍然
We won't get any XP, we won't faint, but we still
回到播放状态
get taken back to the play state.
这就是精灵宝可梦的演示
So that's all for the Pokemon demo.
非常感谢Tony前来演示它
Thanks so much Tony for coming up to demo it.
嗯 这里涉及到很多东西 但正如我们将看到的
Well, there's a lot of pieces involved here, but as we will see,
一旦我们实施了大量这样的基础性项目
once we have a lot of these sort of foundational pieces implemented,
开始对越来越多的这些进行分层并不是太困难
it's not too difficult to start layering more and more of these
让游戏变得更加丰富
onto the game to make it even more rich.
事实上 我们的任务是--
In fact, the assignment is to--
我们将在最后看到这一点 我将在最后回顾一下--
and we'll see this at the end, I'll recap this at the end--
但作业的目标是让你实现一个菜单--
but the assignments goal is for you to implement a menu--
类似于我们看到的显示战斗和逃跑的菜单--
similar to the menu that we saw where fight and run were shown--
这将显示您的每个统计数据的当前统计数据
that will show you what your current stat is for each of your stats,
有进攻、防守、速度和你的HP
there's attack, defense, speed, and your HP.
它将显示您在升级前的状态 数量
It will show you what your stat is before leveling, the amount
它将增加 然后是最终的金额
that it will increase by, and then the final amount,
这有点类似于实际的精灵宝可梦游戏的工作原理
which is sort of similar to how the actual Pokemon games work,
所以你可以看到 而不是仅仅看到 哦 我把我的级别从5增加到6
so you can see rather than just seeing, oh I increased my level from 5 to 6,
6到7 你可以看到 哦 我的力量从12增加到14
6 to 7, you can see, oh, my strength increased from 12 to 14.
我更强壮一点 我会在下一场比赛中造成更大的伤害
I'm a little bit stronger, I'm going to do more damage on the next play
穿过
through.
所以我们的目标是 我们要看看场上的状态 比赛
So our goal here, we're going to take a look at the field state, the play
状态和战斗状态
state, and the battle state.
在大多数这类游戏中都有一个常见的二分法
And there's a common dichotomy in most of these sorts of games,
无论是《最终幻想》、《寻龙诀》还是《精灵宝可梦》
be it Final Fantasy, or Dragon Quest, or Pokemon
在有田野的地方 你在走来走去
where there is a field, where you are walking around,
你的角色与一个有NPC的游戏世界互动 穿过城镇
you're character interacting with a game world with NPCs, going through towns,
那你有什么
and what have you.
然后是战斗模式 一种战斗状态
And then a battle mode, sort of a battle state
在那里你实际上是在与某种敌人作战
where you're actually fighting against some sort of enemy,
或一系列的敌人 一个党或一个单一的生物
or a series of enemies, a party or a single creature.
因此 我们实现了这两种方法的简单版本 以说明
And so we've implemented simple versions of both of these to illustrate
以及它们之间的过渡
and also the transitions between them.
在我们开始之前 我想做另一种插头
Before we start, I want to make another sort of plug
对于这本Howtomakeanrpg.com 这本书 我其实从中学到了很多
for this howtomakeanrpg.com, this book, I actually learned a lot from this
以及在游戏开发环境中使用Lua
and about using LUA in the context of game development.
我在之前的一节课上提到了这一点
And I pitched this I think in one of the earlier lectures,
但如果你想更深入地研究其中的许多概念
but if you want a deeper dive into a lot of these constructs,
为了对你可能如何做一些事情有一个感觉 比如剪辑场景
and to sort of get a sense for how you might do something like cut scenes,
或者更复杂的战斗布局 更像是--
or more complicated battle layouts, and a lot more like--
它深入到了很多令人惊叹的事情的细节中
it goes into a lot of detail about a lot of awesome things,
一定要去看看
definitely check it out.
它不是免费的 但如果你对这种类型感兴趣 就像我一样
It's not free, but if you're interested in this genre, which I am,
这绝对是值得的
it's definitely worthwhile.
这是我们将成为的精灵床单的样子
Here's what the sprite sheets look like that we'll be
用于这种演示
using for this sort of demonstration.
除了精灵宝可梦 它们都是单独的纹理
The Pokemon aside, which are individual textures.
在这里 我们使用一个简单的精灵工作表 它
Here we're using a simple sprite sheet, which
只有一堆瓷砖 大部分我们都没有用过
just has a bunch of tiles, most of which we did not use.
请注意 灌木丛和高高的草丛没有任何类型的背景
Note that the bush, the tall grass is not on any sort of background.
因此 我们需要分层 基本上
And therefore, we need to layer, basically
有两个单独的瓷砖地图 而不是一个 我们上次没有做
have two separate tile maps as opposed to one, which we didn't do last time.
我们重复使用了塞尔达演讲中使用的精灵纸
And we were reusing the sprite sheet that we used in the Zelda lecture.
以前 我们用它来对付所有的敌人 骷髅 幽灵
Before, we used it for all the enemies, the skeletons, ghosts,
还有泥巴 等等
and slimes, et cetera.
但现在我们实际上是在它所包含的PC上使用它
But now we're actually using it for the PCs that it contains.
具体地说 就是这里的男性全国人大 这是我们的主角
Specifically, just the male NPC here, which is our main character.
我们在本课程中使用的基础类
The foundational class that we're using in this lecture
其他的一切都围绕着它 让它发挥作用
that sort of everything else revolves around and makes this work
是状态堆栈
is the state stack.
所以在此之前 我们拥有的是一个国家机器 对吧
And so before, what we had was a state machine, right,
我们一次只在一个州
where we were in one state at a time.
所以你几乎可以想象 我们这里有一个盒子
So you can almost think of it like, we have a box here,
而且它只有一个插座
and it just has one socket.
然后我们总是看着这个插座
And then we're always looking at this one socket,
无论是游戏状态 还是战斗状态
whether it's the play state, or the battle state,
或者某种形式的转变
or a transition of some kind.
现在我们正在过渡到这样的想法 相反
And now we're transitioning into the idea of, instead,
一次只能看到的一种状态 我们会把它堆叠起来
of just one state that we can only see at once, we'll make it a stack.
因此 我们可以做的是 不只是拥有一个
And so what we can do with this is, rather than just having one,
因此 我们可以一次呈现多个状态 对吗？
we can therefore render multiple states at a time, right?
让我们假设这就像赛场 对 或者是比赛状态
So let's say this is like the field, right, or the play state.
也许这就像是一场对话 或者别的什么 对吗？
And then maybe this is like a dialogue, or something, right?
就像我们以前在现场看到的那样 我们有一个文本框
Like we saw before in the field, we had a text box.
我们实际上可以把东西层层叠在一起
We can actually layer things on top of each other.
然后可能这就像是淡出 对 或者淡入
And then maybe this is like a fade out, right, or a fade in.
所以我们可以从播放状态开始 然后我们四处走动
So we start with the play state maybe, and we're walking around,
我们和鼻咽癌里的人互动
and we interact with in NPC.
不是将播放状态转换为对话状态
Rather than transition the play state to a dialog state,
在我们之前的模型中 这将完全消除播放状态
which would, in our previous model, completely eliminate the play state,
因为一次只有一种状态可能是活动的
because there's only one state that could be active at a time.
现在我们只需要呈现 无论堆栈中有多少个状态
Now we just render, however many states we have in our stack,
我们只是根据它们被弹出的顺序按顺序呈现它们
we just render them sequentially based on the order that they were popped in.
我们会先渲染这个 基本上是自下而上渲染
We would rendered this first, we basically render from the bottom up.
呈现播放状态 然后是对话 然后是淡入
Render the play state, then the dialogue, then the fade in.
这将产生一系列不同的事情的效果
And this will have the effect of doing a whole bunch of different things, which
我们将在发行版中看到
we'll see in the distro.
但我们真的只需要一次更新一个州
But we only really ever need to update one state at a time,
对 因为如果我们激活了播放状态和对话状态
right, because if we have the play state active and the dialog state active
以及淡入状态活动 按此顺序 作为堆栈
and the fade in state active, in this order, as a stack,
是的 我们是在推动行动 为了得到一些东西
right, we were pushing the operation for pushing for getting something
把它放到堆栈上称为推送 然后把它取出来
onto the stack is called a push, and getting it off
如果不熟悉就被称为流行音乐
is called a pop if unfamiliar.
如果我们推动所有这些州前进 那么通常情况下
If we're pushing all of these states on, then usually,
我们只需要更新上面的内容 对吗？
we only need to update whatever's on top, right?
例如 如果没有淡入 我们只有
If there's no fade in for example, and we only
使对话状态处于活动状态 或对话和位置
have a dialog state active, or a dialogue and a place
按照从上到下的顺序陈述 然后我们通常
state in that order top to bottom, then we usually
我不想让他更新播放状态的情况
don't want him update what's going on in the play state.
我们只关心正在进行的对话
We're only concerned with the dialogue that's taking place.
我们只想让它接受输入
We only want that to take input.
当我们按空格键、Enter键或其他键时
And when we press Spacebar, Enter, or whatever
按钮清除该对话框状态 我们将其弹出 对
button clears that dialog state, we pop it off, right,
然后我们又回到了游戏状态
and then we're back to the play state.
那么我们只是在更新播放状态
Then we're just updating the play state.
因此能够更新最上面的内容 同时
And so being able to update just what's on top while
能够渲染底部的所有东西
being able to render everything that's on bottom.
这并不适用于所有的博弈公式
And this doesn't hold true for all game formulas,
当然有一些游戏 你可以在其中进行对话和游戏状态
there's certainly some games where you can have a dialogue and a play state
两者都得到了更新 但仍在使用某种状态堆栈
both get updated, but that's still using a state stack of sorts,
你只是在以一种自上而下的方式更新事物
you're just then updating things in a top down way.
但这让我们可以做各种各样的事情 比如过渡
But this allows us to do all kinds of things like transitions,
并保持--比如 我们有一个游戏状态
and preserving-- like for example, the fact that we have a play state
我们可以在上面弹出一个战斗状态
and we can pop a battle state on top of that,
我们看不到它下面的游戏状态
where we don't see the play state underneath it,
我们只看到战斗状态 这一切都在更新
we only see the battle state, and that's all updating.
但如果我们打开战斗状态 我们就
But it is we pop the battle state off, we're
就在我们刚刚处于游戏状态的地方
right back where we just were in the play state.
由于缺乏更好的词语 它从以前就保持了自己的状态
It's preserved its state, for lack of a better word, from before.
这是这个模型为我们提供的舒适的东西
And this is something that this model affords us comfortably.
所以这是某种程度上的基础课程
And so that's sort of the foundational class that's
在这个发行版中实现 这将允许
implemented in this distro, which will allow
让我们做各种很棒的事情
us to do all kinds of awesome things.
那么让我们继续下去 看看它是什么样子的
So let's go ahead and take a look at what that looks like.
我在这里打开了州堆栈
I have state stack open here.
所以状态堆栈在这里只有一组状态
So state stack has just a set of states here.
然后 当我们想要插入一个状态时
And then whenever we want to insert a state,
它将位于状态堆栈的末尾
it's going to be at the end of the state stack.
所以这将是最后一次--
So it's going to be whatever the last--
因此 如果我们将其视为表格中的一系列州
so if we're looking at it as a series of states in a table,
它将是表中最后一个索引
it'll be whatever the last index is in the table.
这将是我们的 我们堆栈的顶部
That will be our, the top of our stack.
如果你愿意 你可以用相反的方式来实现这一点
And you can implement this either way in reverse if you wanted to.
只是更简单 因为你只需做一张简单的桌子 移走即可摆脱
It's just easier, because you can just do a simple table.remove to get rid
在--
of the--
表 删除该表以消除最后一个状态
table.remove on that table to get rid of the last state
而不需要把所有的东西都搬回去
without having to shift back everything.
所以如果我们从第一个索引开始 你必须把所有的东西都移回去
So if we did it starting at index one, you'd have to shift everything back.
这也会有一点奇怪 因为你会从一个开始
And it would also be a little bit weird, because you would start at one,
然后事情就会向左转
and then things would go left.
但基本上 为了更新我们的最终状态
But basically, in order to update whatever our end state is,
我们只在#self.States执行操作 无论我们的状态堆栈有多大
we just do at #self.states, which will be however large our state stack is,
我们只是调用该状态的更新
we just call update on that state.
然后处理人工智能就在这里 尽管我们没有使用它
And then process AI is here, although we're not using it.
但如果你有人工智能 事情就会是一样的
But if you had AI, it would be the same thing
基本上是对您所在州的人工智能的更新
as basically an update for artificial intelligence for your state.
而不是一次只呈现一种状态
Rather than rendering just one state at a time,
我们在这里迭代我们所有的状态
we iterate through all of our states here
使用iPair 它将对它们进行数值迭代
using ipairs, which will iterate through them numerically
从一开始一直到最后
starting at one going to the end.
所以我们调用istate 并对其进行自我状态呈现
So we call for istate, and ipairs of self.state, render it,
因此 这将使所有内容从前到后 或从下到上
so that will render everything back to front, or bottom to top,
并允许我们得到这个分层的外观
and allow us to get this layered look where
例如 我们有一个游戏状态在下面进行
we have a play state going on underneath for example,
然后是上面的一段对话
and then a dialogue on top.
或者我们有一个战斗状态在最顶端
Or we have a battle state going at the very top,
也许战斗状态本身就推动了一场对话
and maybe that battle state itself pushes a dialogue
状态到堆栈的顶部 或一堆其他状态
state to the top of the stack, or a bunch of other states,
一个过渡 你想要什么都行
a transition, whatever you would like.
要清除它 我们只需将表重置为空表
To clear it, we just reset the table to an empty table.
要推送状态 我们只需在该状态上执行插入操作 然后
To push a state, we just do an insert on that state, and then
我们在该状态下调用Enter
we call enter on that state.
正如我们以前所做的 有点类似于状态机 当我们更改状态时
As we did before, sort of similarly with state machine, when we changed a state,
我们会对它调用Enter和Exit 但现在我们
we would call enter on it and exit, but now we're
当我们按下时 只需按回车键
just calling enter when we push.
然后 我们所要做的就是在任何地方调用Exit
And then to pop, all we do is call exit on whatever
最后一个状态在我们的状态堆栈中 然后
the last state is in our state stack, and then just
对self.States调用Table.Remove
call table.remove on self.states.
默认情况下 当您在一个表上调用Table.Remove时 只需要一个表
And by default, when you call table.remove on a table, just a table
没有其他参数 它将删除所有
with no other arguments, it'll remove whatever
最后一个索引是该表的索引
the last index is of that table.
这说得通吗？
Does that makes sense?
有没有人对状态堆栈的工作原理有任何疑问？
Anybody have any questions as to how the state stack works?
好的 太棒了
All right, awesome.
那么让我们来看看开始状态
So let's take a look then at the start state.
这就是开始的日期
So this is the start date.
非常简单 我们只有几个文本标签
Fairly simple, we just have a couple of text labels,
然后我们有一个随机分配的从左到右的精灵
and then we have just a randomly assigned sprite going left to right.
我们认为我们是如何实现这场运动的？
How do we think we're achieving the movement?
是的 定时器 然后我们就开始画画
Yep, timer.tween, and then we're just drawing
一个椭圆形 对 很简单
an ellipse, right, pretty simple.
然后当我们按Enter键时 请注意转换
And then when we press Enter, note the transition.
请注意 有一个淡入淡出到白色 然后淡出到透明
Notice that there's a fade to white, and then fade to transparent.
所以如果我们回想起我们看第三场比赛的时候 我们是怎么做的
And so if we recall from when we looked at match three, how do we do this,
我们还记得吗？
do we remember?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
演讲者1：没错 长方形存放在哪里？
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, and the rectangle was stored where?
抱歉 对摄像机重复一遍 我们有一个长方形
Sorry, to repeat for the camera, we had a rectangle
它充满了整个屏幕 我们只是在它的透明度之间补间
that filled the entire screen, and we just tween the transparency for it,
这是真的
which is true.
不过 之前存储在那里的矩形
The rectangle there before though was stored
当时处于活动状态的状态 就像开始日期一样
in whatever state was active at the time, which was like the start date,
或者我认为开始游戏状态是它的名字
or the I think begin game state was the name.
在过渡过程中不一定相关的实际状态
The actual state that wasn't necessarily relevant at the transition.
但使用状态堆栈 我们实际上可以将这一想法分离
But using a state stack, we can actually decouple this idea.
我们可以采用过渡的概念 因为想象一下
We can take the concept of a transition, and because imagine
如果我们想要在每个单独的州之间进行转换
if we wanted to make a transition between every single state
在我们的游戏中存在的东西 对吗？
that existed in our game, right?
如果我们想从战场过渡到战场
If we wanted to transition from the battle to the field,
或者战场 或者任何我们可能想要的东西 比如开始
or the field to the battle, or whatever else we might want, like the start
到场上 我们需要在每一块中都有一个矩形
to the field, we would need a rectangle in every single one
我们正在跟踪的那些具有不透明性的
of those that has an opacity that we're keeping track of.
这并不一定与该州的目的密切相关 对吗？
And that's not necessarily germane to the purpose of that state, right?
因此 因为我们现在有一个状态堆栈 所以我们实际上可以
So because we now have a state stack, we can actually
抽象出这个过渡的概念 并把它变成自己的状态
abstract out this idea of a transition, and turn it into its own state.
我们可以有一个过渡态
We can have a transition state.
回想一下 因为我们只是将所有东西分层
And recall that since we're just layering everything
[?关闭？]所有这些状态 我们正在按顺序呈现它们
[? off ?] all these states, and we're rendering them sequentially,
具有自己的状态 例如 不透明矩形
having a state that possesses it's own for example, opacity rectangle,
我们可以分层 把它压到堆栈上 然后渲染它
we can just layer that, push that onto the stack, and render that,
它会给我们带来这种转变的错觉
and it'll give us the illusion of having this transition.
但我们实际上不需要让它成为国家的一部分
But we don't need to actually have it be part of the state
我们正试图过渡出和进入的地方
that we're trying to transition out of and into.
这说得通吗？
Does that make sense?
那么让我们来看看 举个例子
So let's take a look, for example, at the--
我们先来看看开始状态
let's take a look at the start state first,
只是为了让我们看看这是从哪里开始的
just so we can see where that actually gets kicked off.
所以开始状态 我们开始一些音乐 我们有一个精灵
So the start state, we kick off some music, we have a sprite,
还有一个精灵x和y
and a sprite x and y.
实际上 这些值与正在移动的精灵有关
These are values that are relevant to the sprite that's moving, actually,
我们只有一个精灵从左向右移动
we only have one sprite ever moving left to right.
它只是被传送到屏幕的右边
It just gets teleported to the right edge of the screen
一旦它被带到一边
as soon as it gets taken to one edge.
所以我们只有一个精灵 一个x和y
So we only have one sprite, one x and y.
然后每隔三秒 就像我们在这里看到的那样
And then every three seconds as we see here,
我们有一个回调函数 它将补间精灵x到负64
we have a callback function that will tween the sprites x to negative 64
超过0.2秒 真的很快
over 0.2 seconds, so really quickly.
然后在完成后 将其传送到右侧
And then on finish, teleport it to the right.
然后做同样的事情 但在它之间
And then do the same exact thing, but tween it
在0.2秒内到达中心
to the center over 0.2 seconds.
然后我们一按Enter或Return键 请注意
And then as soon as we press Enter or Return, note this here,
我们有gStateStack 而不再是gStateMachine
we have gStateStack, not a gStateMachine anymore,
我们正在推动它在州内逐渐淡出
and we're pushing on to it a fade in state,
它接受一个RGB、一个持续时间和一个回调函数
which takes an RGB, a duration, and a callback function.
现在 如果你看看main.lua 这是相关的
Now if you look at main.lua, this is relevant,
因为现在我们不再有状态机了 对吗？
because now we no longer have a state machine, right?
我们之前有一个全局状态机gStateMachine
We previously had a global state machine, gStateMachine.
我们会给它一个进入函数、匿名函数的索引列表
We would give it a list of indexes into functions, anonymous functions.
它们将返回一个状态的实例化
Those would return the instantiation of a state.
然后 当我们调用Change时 状态机将
And then when we called change, the state machine will
索引到其状态列表中 并调用匿名函数
index into its list of states, and call that anonymous function,
这将导致将状态改变为某种状态
which would have the result of changing the state to some state
我们已经实现为一个类 对吧？
that we've implemented as a class, right?
现在我们只需要创建一个状态栈
Now we just create a state stack and we just
将一个新的起始状态推送到类中
push a new start state onto the class.
所以这实际上是同样的事情 只是现在
And so what this will do is effectively the same thing, only now
我们可以把事情放在开始状态 对吧 或者播放状态
we can layer things onto the start state, right, or play state,
或者任何我们想要的东西 我们永远也摆脱不了它
or whatever we want to, and we're not going to ever get rid of it.
我是说 我们可以摆脱它 但我们不需要
I mean, we can get rid of it, but we don't have to.
对于游戏状态 特别是 我们希望它几乎永远不会
For the play state, especially, we want that to pretty much never get
从堆栈中弹出 因为
popped off the stack, because that's going
保护我们所有的信息
to preserve all of our information.
我们将回到默认状态来存储所有的角色信息
We're going to default back to that to store all of our character information,
我们的口袋妖怪信息 无论我们还能
our Pokemon information, whatever else we might
想在这个游戏的外壳上添加一个库存
want to add onto this shell of a game in inventory,
等等 一个世界性的国家
et cetera, a world state at large.
我们希望保持这一点 并在我们所有的战斗中保持一致
We want to preserve that and keep that consistent across all of our battle
国家等等
states and so forth.
战斗状态会从那个世界获取信息
And the battle states will just pull information from that world,
从游戏状态中 根据需要构建一场战斗
from that play state, and construct a battle as needed.
这有道理吗
Does that makes sense?
好了 现在我们实际上是 我们对main做的唯一真正的更改
OK, so here we're effectively, the only real changes we've made to main
不再是一个状态机 现在我们有一个状态栈
are no longer a state machine, now we have a state stack,
我们要推动启动状态
going to push start state, that start state
有一些行为 就像我们之前实现的任何其他状态一样
has some behavior just like any other state that we've implemented before.
我之前要讲的是起始状态的第36行
And what I was about to get into before was here on line 36 of the start state,
我们正在把另一个状态推入堆栈
we're pushing another state onto the stack.
所以已经有一个起始状态了 它是从起始状态本身内部
So there's already a start state, and it's from within the start state itself
事实上
actually.
我们要把这个堆栈 它只有一层深
We're going to take that stack, which is just one level deep,
现在我们要把它变成两层深
and then we're going to make it two levels deep now.
所以现在我们要添加一个淡入状态
So now we're going to add a fade in state.
我们可以看到 淡入状态是一个RGB
And the fade in state as we can see, takes in an RGB.
有没有人猜到RGB与什么有关？
Does anybody have a guess as to what the RGB is relevant for?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
演讲者1：你想用黑色还是白色来淡出？
SPEAKER 1: To whether you want to fade in black or white?
是的 任何颜色
Yes, any color.
如果我们愿意 我们可以把它变成红色
We can make this, we can make it a fade to red if we wanted to,
或褪色为蓝色
or fade to blue.
但我们不必为淡入淡出创建两个单独的类
But we don't have to create two separate classes for a fade in white,
淡入黑淡出黑淡出白
fade in black, fade out black, fade out white.
我们可以给它一个颜色
We can just give it a color.
我的意思是 我们甚至可以更进一步
And then I mean, we could even go a level further with this,
并使其具有不透明性 这样我们就不需要淡入状态
and make it take in an opacity as well, so that we don't need a fade in state,
或者淡出状态 我们只需要一个淡出状态 对吧
or a fade out state, we just need a fade state, right?
褪色状态将决定 基于任何
And the fade state will determine, based on whatever
最后一个不透明度参数 我们给它 正确的方式淡入淡出
last opacity parameter we give it, the right way to fade in and out.
但在这种情况下 淡入状态
But in this case, the difference between the fade in state
并且淡出状态是人们知道去到0 人们知道去到255
and the fade out state is one knows to go to 0, one knows to go to 255.
这是唯一的关键区别
That's really the only key difference.
然后这个1 持续时间 对 我们需要告诉它褪色多久
And then this 1, the duration, right, we need to tell it how long to fade.
最后一点是函数
And then this last bit here is a function.
我们给它一个匿名函数 这是一个回调函数
We're giving it an anonymous function, this is a callback function,
因为淡入状态本质上是异步状态
because the fade in state by nature is an asynchronous state.
它的行为会随着时间的推移而改变
It does its behavior over time.
所以我们需要一种方式 我们需要告诉它 好的
So we need a way, we need to tell it, OK,
当你完成了你正在做的事情 调用这段代码
when you finished doing what you're doing, call this bit of code
这样我们就可以做一些事情 而不是立即
here, so that we can do something not immediately,
我们可以推迟它的执行
we can sort of defer its execution till later.
这是我们在这节课中会看到的共同点
And this is something that we'll see common throughout this lecture,
因为我们也在类似的对话中实现了这一点
because we have this implemented also in like dialogue for example,
因为我们不知道用户什么时候会在对话框上按空格键
because we don't know when the user is going to press Spacebar on the dialog
把窗户关上
state and clear the window.
但如果我们想要那扇窗 想要清除对话
But what if we want that window, the clearing of that dialog
引发某种事件对吧
to trigger some sort of event, right?
例如 如果他们在战斗中按回车键
For example, if they press Enter when they're in the battle,
我们想让它进入下一个行动
we want it to go to the next action.
我们不一定知道它什么时候会发生
We don't necessarily know when it's going to happen,
所以我们只需要向对话状态传递一个匿名函数
so we'll just pass in an anonymous function to that dialogue state
每当在该对话框上调用Close函数时 类都将调用
that the class will call whenever the close function is called on that dialog
州政府
state.
它说 当关闭时 执行这个匿名函数
It says, when closed, execute this anonymous function.
然后那个匿名函数就可以做你想做的任何事情
And then that anonymous function can do whatever you want to do.
它可能会将其他几个状态弹出到堆栈上
It could pop another other several states onto the stack.
但这就是允许我们链接异步行为的原因
But this is what allows us to chain asynchronous behavior.
这是这里的关键
That's the key here.
所以这个匿名函数--所以我们现在来看一下
So this anonymous function-- so we'll take a look now actually
在淡入状态 这样我们就可以看到这是什么样子的
at the fade in state, just so we can see what this looks like.
所以我们在这里看到 褪色状态 对 吸收颜色
So we see here, fade in state, right, takes in the color.
我们以前看到过 那将是我们褪色的颜色
We saw before, that will be the color we fade to.
我们实际执行转换所需的时间长度
The length of time that it'll take us to actually perform the transition.
我们用什么来过渡 我们认为 Timer Tweet 对吗？
And what are we using for the transition do we think, timer.tween, right?
所以我们实际上要做的大部分事情
So most everything that we'll do actually
在这堂课的整个过程中 都有异步行为
throughout the course of this lecture that has asynchronous behavior,
我们可以用定时器来实现它 这很好
we can implement it with timer, which is nice.
它允许我们相当简洁和声明地告诉
It allows us to fairly succinctly and declaratively tell
准确地说出了我们希望随着时间的推移而发生的事情
right out what exactly we want to have happen over time.
在这种情况下 我们将在一段时间内
In this case, we're going to tween over the course of time
把我们自己的不透明度提高到255
the opacity of our self to 255.
所以淡入会淡入我们所有东西的全色
So the fade in is going to fade into the full color of whatever we
已经把它给了
have given it.
因此它将从0(默认情况下显示在这里)到255
So it's going to go from 0, which is shown here by default, to 255.
然后我们一拍完那个小插曲
And then as soon as we finish that tween,
这就是我们弹出淡入状态的时候
that is when we pop the fade in state.
我们将有效地把我们自己从州里跳出来 从堆栈中跳出来
We're going to pop ourselves off the state effectively, off the stack
有效地
effectively.
然后在这里 我们呼吁淡出完成
And then here, we're calling on fade complete.
这就是匿名函数所在的位置
And that's where the anonymous function is.
在淡入淡出时 完成被传递到这里
On fade complete is passed in here.
因此 通过将该函数放入补间操作的结束函数中
So by putting that function into the finish function of the tween operation,
我们允许自己推迟我们在--中写的函数
we've allowed ourselves to defer that function that we've written up in the--
它处于启动状态
it's in the start state.
我们将此函数的执行推迟到补间操作之后
We defer the execution of this function until after that tween operation
发生了
takes place.
这说得通吗？
Does that make sense?
好的 太棒了
OK, awesome.
这实际上就是它的本质
And that's effectively what it is.
这是一个共同的主题 如果你浏览一下发行版 我们会看到这一点
And that's a common theme that we'll see if you're looking through the distro,
你会在很多地方看到它
you'll see it in a lot of places.
匿名函数或回调函数
Anonymous functions or callback functions
而是被传递到对话和淡出之类的东西中
rather being passed into things like the dialogs, and the fades,
还有其他几个地方
and a few other places.
例如 在轮流状态中 有
In the take turns state for example, there's
也接受回调函数的函数
a function that takes in at a callback function as well.
这是您可以有效地链接异步行为的方式
And that's effectively how you can chain asynchronous behavior that
随着时间的推移执行 而不是被阻塞
executes over time, rather than it being blocking.
到目前为止 有没有人对这是如何运作的有任何疑问？
Does anybody have any questions so far as to how this works, at all?
好了 当淡入淡出后--
All right, so when the fade is done--
我们仍然是这里的起点--
we're still the start state here--
在这一点上 淡出完成 我们正在执行这个匿名函数
at this point, the fade is done, we're executing this anonymous function.
在本例中 我们将从堆栈中弹出Start状态
We're going to pop the start state off of the stack in this case.
然后我们要推动一个--
And then we're going to push a--
我们要在这里做两个推力
we're going to do two pushes here.
一种是推动一种播放状态 这就是NPC[INAUDIBLE]
One is to push a play state, which recall is where the NPC [INAUDIBLE]
走来走去的角色
character walking around.
还有一个就是推动对话状态
And another one is to push a dialogue state.
因此 这将产生的影响是 而不是我们
And so what this will have the effect of doing is rather than us
立即进入玩耍状态 能够四处走动
immediately going into the play state and being able to walk around,
我们实际上置身于一个
we're actually put right into a world where
有一条消息等着我们 我们有
there is a message waiting for us that we have
按Enter On以继续
to press Enter on in order to continue.
当我们按回车键时 因为我们先按播放状态
And when we press Enter, because we're pushing the play state first,
然后是对话状态 对话状态
and then the dialogue state, the dialogue state
在堆栈的顶部 对吧 因为
is at the top of the stack, right, because things
就像一堆盘子一样被推上来
get pushed onto like a stack of plates.
你把一个游戏状态牌放在底部 然后在上面放另一个牌
You put a play state plate on the bottom and then another plate on top,
在这种情况下 这块板就是对话状态
and that plate is the dialogue state in this case.
而你只能与顶层互动--
And you can only interact with the top--
在此型号中 我们一次只更新顶板
we're only updating the top plate at once in this model.
很明显 我们可以制造一个更复杂的状态
We could obviously make a more complicated state
堆栈允许我们同时更新多层状态
stack that allows us to have several layers of states being updated at once,
但为了简单起见 我们只选择允许更新顶层
but for simplicity, we only opted to allow the top layer to be updated.
对话状态将是活动状态
The dialog state is going to be the active state,
它将接收输入
it's going to be receiving input.
它们都将被渲染 所以我们
All of them are going to be rendered, so we're
要自下而上地渲染
going to render things from the bottom up.
我们将呈现播放状态 然后
We're going to render the play state, then
我们将呈现对话状态 但对话状态的
we're going to render the dialog state, but the dialog state's
会变得活跃起来
going to be active.
我们只能对该州的任何事情进行施压
We're only going to be able to press anything on that state.
最后 实际上 甚至超越了对话状态
And then lastly, actually, even beyond the dialogue state,
我们正在推动另一个州 我们正在推动一个淡出的州
we're pushing another state, we're pushing a fade out state.
在这种情况下 它与淡出状态相反
And in this case, it's the opposite of the fade in state,
它只需要一个RGB 我们将从255不透明度
it just takes in an RGB, and we'll go from 255 opacity
在这种情况下为零不透明度
to zero opacity in that case.
因此 这使得我们能够做正确的事情
And so what that allows us to do for playing right,
我们现在处于开始状态 按Enter键
we're here in the start state, pressing Enter.
这就是我们在州里的淡出
That's our fade in state was there.
然后我们进入了游戏状态、对话状态和淡出状态
And then we pushed to the play state and the dialogue state and the fade
所以你几乎会认为
out state at once, so you would almost think
我们推入淡入 然后淡出
that we push a fade in and then the fade out,
但我们必须先奠定基础 然后才能
but we have to lay that foundation before we
将淡出状态放在堆栈的顶部
put the fade out state on top of the stack,
对 因为最上面的层被更新了
right, because the top layer gets updated.
所以我们必须把淡出状态放在所有这些状态之上
So we have to push the fade out state on top of all of those.
它会被更新 会淡出
That will get updated, that will fade out,
然后我们回到我们推动的两个州
and then we're back to the two states that we push
在我们推入淡出状态之前
before we pushed the fadeout state.
那是从那以后的事吗？
Does that make since?
好的
OK.
有没有人对这种流动是如何运作的有任何疑问？
Does anybody have any questions as to how that sort of flow works?
凉爽的
Cool.
好吧 这就是背后的主旨 我的意思是
All right, so that's the gist behind, I mean,
这基本上是我们今天所做的事情的核心
that's essentially the core of what we're doing today
是推送多个状态的状态堆栈
is the state stack pushing multiple states.
然后只需弄清楚正确的顺序
And then just figuring out the right order
需要把它们推进去才能得到你想要的外观
the need to push them in to get the desired appearance that you want,
对吗？
right?
当我们处于开始状态时 我们按下淡出状态
We push the fade out state while we're in the start state,
或者更确切地说 是在状态中褪色
or fade in state rather.
这将把我们带到白色 然后像排序
That will take us to white, and then like sort
几乎就像在幕后--在幕后 我们打开了一切
of, almost like underneath the-- behind the curtain, we're popping everything,
然后我们添加戏剧 对话 然后另一个淡出
and then we're adding the play, dialogue, and then another fade out
州政府
state.
因此 你必须平衡你把东西放在一起的顺序
And so you sort of have to balance the order that you put things in in order
以达到预期的效果
to achieve the desired results.
它不一定和你直觉上的一模一样
It may not necessarily be exactly as you intuitively
想一想 直到你想到我们是如何更新和渲染的
think until you think about just how we're updating and rendering
堆积如山的东西
things on a stack.
所以这是我认为真正感到舒适的终极障碍
And so that's the ultimate hurdle I think in really getting comfortable
但一旦你得到了它 其他的一切都会下降
with the distro, but once you've gotten that, everything else sort of falls
就位
into place.
以及丰富的异步函数 正如我们将介绍的
That and the sort of abundance of asynchronous functions, as we'll
我们很快就会看到图形用户界面 以及我们是如何实现
see pretty shortly when we look at GUIs, and how we've implemented
很多基本的图形用户界面功能
a lot of basic GUI functionality.
其中很大一部分是非常、非常受回拨驱动的
A lot of that is very, very call back driven,
只是因为它的本质是基于用户输入的 对吗？
just because of the nature of it being based on user input, right?
你不知道用户什么时候会做任何输入
You don't know when the user's going to do any input,
因此 无论图形用户界面代码发生什么情况 请将其推迟
so defer whatever happens with that GUI code
在用户按空格键时所涉及的触发器的情况下
with the triggers involved when the user presses Spacebar,
输入 然后调用已传递到该图形用户界面小部件中的函数
Enter, and then call that function that you've passed into that GUI widget.
好了 我们来看看状态堆栈
All right, so we've taken a look at the state stack.
我们已经看了开始状态 淡入状态
We've taken a look at the start state, the fade in state,
现在让我们来看看播放状态
let's take a look now at the play state.
所以游戏状态--
So the play state--
这其中有很多实际上非常类似于
a lot of this is actually very similar to what
我们回到了塞尔达 这是一款非常类似的自上而下的游戏
we did back with Zelda, which is a very similar type of game top down.
观点 唯一的区别是这种性质的RPG--
View, the only difference really with that was RPGs of this nature--
《最终幻想》、《精灵宝可梦》、《寻龙诀》
Final Fantasy, Pokemon, Dragon Quest, they're
平铺到你移动的均匀程度就是平铺
tile based to the degree of even your movement is tile based.
因此 我们在这堂课中努力实现了这一点
And so we've striven to implement that with this lecture.
所以当我们移动我们的球员 我们的角色时
So when we move our player, our character,
例如 它没有像塞尔达那样的自由运动
it doesn't have free motion like we did with Zelda for example.
所以我将演示这一点
So I'll demonstrate this.
所以我可以转到这里的场状态 播放状态 抱歉
So I can go to the field state here, the play state, sorry.
然后当我移动时 如果我按向右 他
And then when I move, if I press right, he
以完美的栅格间隔朝该方向移动
moves in that direction at a perfect grid interval.
所以如果我往上走 我的手就会立刻离开
So if I move up, I'm taking my hand instantly away,
他将继续前进 他将坚守在这个网格上
he's going to keep moving, and he's going to stick hard set to this grid.
这只是这些游戏实现的一种趋势
And that's just a sort of trend that these games have implemented.
它允许您与网格保持完美一致 并帮助您
It allows you to stay perfectly aligned with the grid, and helps you
我想某些游戏--
I guess certain game--
我认为这可能不是严格意义上的
I don't think it's strictly necessary for probably
大多数选择实现这一点的游戏
most of the games that choose to implement this.
我认为这是NES和GameBoy基于瓷砖的游戏的症状
I think it was a symptom of tile based games from the NES and Gameboy
更易于设计和实现的时代
era being easier to design and implement,
因为它们是非常基于磁贴的系统
because they're very tile based systems.
但我的意思是 即使作为一种审美选择 我认为它也是有意义的
But I mean, even as an aesthetic choice, I suppose it makes sense,
因为一切都非常完美地排列在一起
because everything aligns very perfectly.
所以这就是这场比赛中球场状态的核心区别
So that's the core difference really with the field state in this game.
那么 我们如何着手实现这样的网格对齐移动系统呢
So how can we go about implementing a grid aligned movement system like this
与我们的球员相比 我们在塞尔达是如何做到这一点的？
with our player relative to how we did it in Zelda for example?
我们是怎么想的--当然 是吗？
How do we think-- sure yeah?
观众：所以我们没有x和y 我们只有瓷砖的位置
AUDIENCE: So we don't x and y's, we just have the tile positions.
演讲者1：所以你没有x和y 我们只有平铺位置
SPEAKER 1: So you don't have x and y's, we just have the tile positions.
接近 我会说它更专注于瓷砖的位置
Close, I would say it's more focused on the tile positions,
但你仍然需要一个x和一个y 因为你仍然
but you still do need an x and a y, because you still
需要在那个准确的位置画出那个精灵
need to draw that sprite at that exact position.
对吧 托尼？
Right, yes Tony?
观众：嗯 当你需要移动精灵的时候
AUDIENCE: Well, when you need to move the sprite, instead
每次更新时都会移动 在两个磁贴位置之间进行补间
of moving at every update, you tween it between the two tile locations.
演讲者1：完全正确 所以与其移动精灵
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, so rather than moving the sprite
在每次更新的准确像素位置 您可以在收到输入时补间精灵
at exact pixel positions per update, you tween the sprite when you receive input
到一个特定的位置
to a specific location.
然后我们实际上也在这一点上停止了输入
And then we actually stop input at that point as well.
当我们不完全处于给定的块时 我们没有任何输入的用处
There's no use for us having any input when we're not exactly at a given tile,
所以当他有效地行走时 我们禁用输入
so we disable input while he's walking effectively.
所以这是实现的 如果我们查看实体中的发行版
And so this is implemented, if we're looking at the distro in the entity
同学们 这里有一个--
class, there is a--
我相信它就在这里--
I believe it's in here--
可能是玩家 等一下
maybe player, hold on.
哦 对不起 不是实体行走状态 不是实体
Oh sorry, no it's entity walk state, not the entity.
实体只是相关信息的容器
Entity is just a container for the information that's relevant.
因此 在实体漫游状态下 我们尝试移动
So here in the entity walk state, we have attempt move.
因此 尝试移动所做的基本上是
And so what attempt move does is essentially
它看起来是为了确保我们在地图的范围内 对吗？
it looks to make sure that we're within the bounds of the map, right?
然后 如果我们是--
And then if we are--
这个游戏中的每个实体现在都有一个地图y和x 以及一个常规的y和x
every entity in this game now has a map y and x, and a regular y and x.
所以正规的y和x 我们仍然需要
And so the regular y and x, we still need in order
在地图上的特定位置绘制我们的精灵
to draw our sprite at a specific location on the map.
我们仍然需要把它画在240多到230多之间 对吗？
We still need to draw it going between 240 something and 230 something, right?
但我们需要一个地图x和一个地图y来表示 好的
But we need a map x and a map y to basically say, OK,
精灵应该在地图上的这个位置
the sprite should be at this position on the map.
然后我们就把它夹在位置乘以16之间
And then we'll just tween it between that position times 16,
这是位置加上或减去x或y
and it's the position plus or minus x or y
乘以16 这将给出我们确切的x和y值
times 16, which will give us the exact x and y value that we
需要把它画到地图上
need to draw it onto the map.
这就是我们在这里做的事情
And so that's what we're doing here.
因此 我们将在输入时调用尝试移动
So were going to call attempt move on input.
所以每当我们做任何输入时--
So anytime we do any input--
这是在游戏者身上完成的 或者是游戏者 是的 游戏者
and this is done in the player like idle, or player, yeah, player
闲置班级--
idle class--
玩家空闲状态
player idle state.
我们将动画更改为编写动画
We change the animation to write animation.
然后我们得到了当前的地图x和y
And then we get it's current map x and y.
然后根据玩家所看的方向
And then based on whatever direction the player is looking,
或者实体正在寻找 我们可以将其用于NPC类或类似的类
or the entity is looking, we could use this for an NPC class, or the like.
我们只需修改2x和2y即可
We just modify our 2x and 2y.
因此 2x和2y将是我们向16倍递增的值
So to 2x and 2y is going to be the value that we're tweening towards times 16,
对吗？
right?
因此 如果我们试图走出地图的边界
And so if we're trying to go outside the map boundaries,
仅仅将我们改回空闲状态不会让我们这样做
just changing us back to idle won't let us do that.
否则 立即将地图y和地图x设置到该位置
Otherwise, set our map y and map x to that position immediately,
对 因为这只是一个减或加一的运算
right, because that's just a minus or plus one operation.
然后在0.5秒的过程中 实际上是补间到那个值
And then over the course of 0.5 seconds, actually tween to that value.
我们可以在这里看到 我们正在调整到瓷砖的大小
And we can see here, we're tweening to the tile size,
实际上是瓷砖大小减去自身的整体高度除以2
and actually to the tile size minus self.entity.height divided by 2.
我们知道这是为什么吗？
Do we know why that is?
我们这样做 是因为如果我们观察现场 我们可以在这里看到
We do that, because if we're looking at the field, we can see here,
注意到我们并没有和草地完美地排成一条线 对吗？
notice that we're not perfectly lined up with the grass, right?
这有点像我们已经超过了它一半
It's kind of like we're halfway above it,
因为这样看起来更自然一点
because it looks just a little bit more natural this way,
这就是大多数游戏的样子
this is how most sort of games look.
如果你在这样的游戏中 你是
And if you're in a game like this and you're
比如靠墙走
like walking up against a wall for example,
这会让你看起来像是
this will allow you to sort of look as if you're
靠着墙 而不是某种
up against the wall rather than sort of being
在墙底的边缘 看起来有点不自然
at the edge of where the bottom of the wall is, and kind of looks unnatural.
这就是为什么我们在那里减去一半的身高
Hence why we minus 1/2 our height right there.
然后当我们完成的时候 我们实际上
And then when we're finished, we actually
测试我们是否仍在按某个键 如果是
test to see whether we're still pressing a key, and if we are,
然后将我们的状态改变为再次行走 这
then change our state to walk again, which
我们将根据我们所关注的方向重复这个过程
we'll just repeat this process depending on which direction we're looking at.
实际上就是这样
And that's effectively it.
这就是我们能够得到这种基于网格的运动的原因
And that's what allows us to get this grid based movement.
对于这是如何工作的 有什么问题吗？
Any questions as to how this works?
凉爽的
Cool.
让我们来看看比赛状态 让我们回到它
Let's take a look then at the play state, let's go back to it.
所以我们有一个级别 这个级别包含我们的实体
So we have a level, the level contains our entity,
它可以包含我们所有的实体 无论是什么
and it can contain all of our entities, and whatever
您希望它包含的对象
objects you want it to contain.
在这种情况下 当我们也处于播放状态时
In this case, when we're in the play state as well,
我们要检查一下是否按P键
we're going to check to see if we press P,
因为这就是召回 我们可以治愈我们的精灵宝可梦
because that's recall, where we can heal our Pokemon,
只是一个小游戏黑客 只是为了让演示变得更容易一点
just a little game hack just to make demoing it a little bit easier.
但如果我们按下P键 我们就会播放治愈音 我们拿出我们的.
But if we press P, we play the heal sound, we take our--
稍后我们会更详细地了解这一点 所有这些
and we'll look a little bit more detail as to this, all this in a little bit.
但邮箱：self.vel.player.pa rty.pokemon@index1.Currenthp
But self.level.player.pa rty.pokemon@index1.currenthp
等于self.vel.player.party.pokemon@1.hp
equals self.level.player.party.pokemon@1.hp.
所以不同的是 目前的惠普是你目前拥有的一切
So the difference is current HP is whatever you currently have,
你可能会受到伤害
you could have taken damage.
无论你的最大生命值是多少 HP都是
HP is whatever your max HP is.
简而言之 这就是你如何获得
And this is like in a nutshell how you get
比如在比赛和RPG中的状态变化 以及健康和MP的差异
like stat changes in games and RPGs, and health and mp differences.
你必须记录所有这些东西的最大值和当前值
You've got to keep track of a max and a current value for all of those things,
然后根据你是被抛光还是被调试
and then depending on whether you're buffed or debugged,
不管你是否受到了伤害 或者是否使用了咒语
or whether you have taken damage or not, or used spells or not,
你可以准确地反映出
you can have an accurate reflection of where
你的角色是 然后总是回到那个状态
your character is and then always return back to that state
当你需要的时候
whenever you need to.
这里有趣的是 稍微复杂一点的事情
The interesting thing here, the slightly more complicated thing
当我们按P键时 我们想要显示一个对话框 上面写着
is when we press P, we want to show a dialog that says,
我将演示这一点 我们想显示一个对话框
and I'll demonstrate this, we want to show a dialog just
就像这个上面说的 我们按下P键 你的精灵宝可梦就被治愈了 对吧？
like this one that says, we press P, your Pokemon has been healed, right?
现在我动不了了
Now I can't move.
我在按箭头键
I'm pressing the arrow keys.
我根本不能移动我的角色 因为这个对话框说--
I can't move my character at all, because this dialog state--
我们处于一个新状态 我们已经将一个新状态推送到状态堆栈中
we're in a new state, well, we've pushed a new state onto the state stack.
这就是这里的对话状态 它取了一个值
And that's the dialog state here, which has taken a value.
因为它是堆栈的顶层 所以它不能更新
And because it's the top layer of the stack, it can't get updated,
或者它正在更新 我们不能更新播放状态 对吧
or it's being updated, and we can't update the play state, right,
基于我们如何建模我们的州堆栈操作 或者它是如何工作的
based on how we've modeled our state stacks operation, or how it works.
然后我一按回车键 它就弹出来了
And then as soon as I press Enter, it gets popped off,
我们刚刚把它搞定了
we've just popped it off.
现在顶部的位置写着 我可以再次移动了
Now the place states at the top, I can move again.
这就是正在发生的事情
So that's what's going on.
因此 对话状态实际上在某种意义上非常类似于淡入淡出
So the dialog state then is actually very similar in a sense, to the fade
进入和淡出状态 请注意 它接受一个匿名函数
in and fade out state in that, notice that it takes an anonymous function.
何时调用此匿名函数？
When does this anonymous function get called?
我们知道吗？
Do we know?
在什么结束的时候？
At the end of what?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
演讲者1：是的 当用户关闭对话框时 正确
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, well, when the user closes the dialog box, correct.
那么 让我们来看看对话状态
So let's take a look at the dialog state then.
我们可以看到 它实际上很简单 很小
And we can see, it's actually pretty simple, it's pretty small.
我们有一条短信和一个回电 对吗？
We have a text that it takes and a callback, right?
这里使用的是文本
The text is used here.
我们实例化 当我们开始研究图形用户界面时 我们将详细了解这一点
We instantiate, and this we'll see in detail when we start looking at GUIs,
以及他们在这里实现的所有窗口小部件
and all the widgets they've implemented here.
该文本框被放置在硬编码位置 并且它接收该文本
This text box gets put at a hard coded position, and it receives this text.
然后我们将self.call回调设置为该回调函数
And then we set our self.callback to that callback function.
如果我们关闭了文本框 这意味着我们将
If we have closed the text box, meaning, we're
查看self.extbox.isClosed 其中
looking to see at self.textbox.isClosed, which
是Text Box类的函数
is a function of the text box class.
如果它已关闭 则执行self.allback 然后弹出
If it's closed, then execute self.callback, and then pop
堆栈的这个对话框状态 对吗？
this dialog state of the stack, right?
所以这在某种意义上是相似的 淡入淡出
So it's similar in a sense, to the fade in and fade out,
然后它接受匿名函数
and then it takes anonymous function.
唯一的区别在于它是如何执行的
The only difference is in how it gets executed.
在淡入状态下 匿名函数
With the fade in state, the anonymous function
在Finish函数结束时被调用 该函数
was called at the end of the finish function, which
是补间对象的一部分
is part of the tween object.
在本例中 我们在以下情况下显式执行回调函数
In this case, we're executing the callback function explicitly when
我们已关闭文本框
we've closed the text box.
因此 我们等待用户输入 而不是等待某个异步操作
So we're waiting for user input versus waiting for some asynchronous operation
才能完成
to finish.
当然 我们称之为文本框呈现
And then of course, we call text box render,
然后 我们将很快看到所有这些方法都是这些小部件的一部分
and then we'll see all of these methods shortly as part of these widgets,
但乍一看 这就是对话状态真正发生的一切
but at a glance, this is all that's really happening with the dialog state.
非常简单 使用我们已有的相同模式
Very simple, using the same pattern that we've
将未来的行为推迟到匿名函数
seen of deferring future behavior to anonymous functions.
关于这是如何运作的 或者到目前为止 有什么问题吗？
Any questions as to how this works, or anything so far?
凉爽的
Cool.
好了 让我们来回顾一下比赛状态
All right, let's take a look back at the play state,
我相信我们快要完成比赛状态了
I believe we're getting close to being finished with the play state.
是的 所以一切 这基本上就是这个游戏中的游戏状态
Yes, so everything, that's basically what the play state is in this game.
然后 许多正在发生的事情也在一定程度上发生
And then a lot of what's going on takes place in a level as well.
所以简而言之 我们有两张地图 两层 对吧
So in a nutshell, we have two maps, two layers, right,
因为瓷砖上的草是它自己的一种[？字母？]
because the grass in the tile sheet is its own sort of [? alphaed ?]
它的周围是透明的
out object, it's got transparency around it.
我们保留了一层基层 下面是一层草
We keep a layer of the base, a layer of the grass underneath,
然后是一个单独的高草层
and then a separate layer for the tall grass.
然后我们就可以看看
And then we can just look and to see when
当我们走过高高的草地时 我们就进入了玩家步行状态
we're walking in the player walk state when we've walked over tall grass.
然后我们需要做什么来开始一个随机相遇？
And then what do we need to do to start a random encounter?
- 是吗-是的
Yes?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
主持人1：是的 我们是如何开始的？
SPEAKER 1: Yes, how do we initiated though?
我们在找什么？
That what are we looking for?
一旦触发战斗状态我们就会立即进入战斗状态
We do push a battle state as soon as we've triggered one,
但我们要怎么触发呢
but how do we trigger one?
我们在找什么？
What are we looking for?
观众：[听不见]球员在草地上
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] player is in the grass.
我不知道是不是因为要搬到新的草地上
I don't know if it's on moving to a new grass,
还是在草地上度过的时光
or if it's time spent in the grass.
是的 我们做一个随机的机会 每当球员在草地上
Yeah, we do a random chance whenever the players on grass.
每当它们开始在草地上行走的时候
And it's whenever they start to walk and there on grass in this case.
但你可以用任何方式 你可以做到这一点
But you can do it either way, you can do it
当他们离开草地 走进草地的时候
when they're leaving the grass, walking into the grass.
在这种情况下 每当你按下按钮
In this case, it's whenever you press the button,
如果他们碰巧在草地上 它会随机选择 概率是十分之一
and they happen to be on grass, it'll do a random chance, one in 10.
如果它等于1 10%的几率会触发遭遇战
And if it's equal to 1, 10% chance it'll trigger an encounter.
这就是触发随机遭遇的要点
So that's the gist behind triggering a random encounter,
很多这样的游戏
and a lot of these games really--
有些游戏是不同的
some games do it differently.
有时候你走得越多
They'll sometimes make it more likely the more steps you've taken,
他们会有一个计数器 说 哦 我走了100步
they'll like sort of keep a counter to say, oh, I've taken 100 steps,
现在应该更有可能了
it should be a lot more likely now.
有些游戏是完全随机的 十分之一 五分之一
Some games will just be completely random, 1 in 10, 1 in 5,
这取决于开发者决定如何实现他们的游戏
depending on how the developers decided to implement their game.
前者更健壮一点
The former is a bit more robust.
但为了简单起见 我们只选择math.random10等于1
But for simplicity, we just chose, math.random10 equals 1.
所以 是的 我们在这里创建瓷砖地图 非常简单
So yeah, we create the tile maps here, pretty straightforward.
然后 实际的随机遭遇发生在玩家步行状态
And then the actual random encountering takes place in the player walk state.
所以这里我们检查了相遇
So here we have check for encounter.
当我们进入行走状态时
And so what this does is whenever we enter the walk state, which
我们是按下按钮进入 还是走进去
is we press the button to enter, or to walk,
调用整个函数 因为我们
this entire function gets called, because we
在状态机中转换到玩家行走状态
do the transition to the player walk state in the state machine.
所有实体仍在使用常规状态机
All of the entities are still using just a regular state machine
而不是状态堆栈
not a state stack.
并不是这次演示所必需的 尽管我确信
Wasn't necessary for this demonstration, though I'm sure
有一些对实体使用状态堆栈的用例
there are some used cases for using a state stack for an entity.
在本例中 我们只使用常规状态机
In this case, we're just using a regular state machine.
因此 当我们更改为Walk状态时 我们将调用Enter 正如我们所看到的
So when we change to the walk state, we are calling enter as we've seen.
然后我们调用self check ForEncount
And then we call self, checkForEncounter.
因此 自己 check ForEncount将设置一个标志
And so self, checkForEncounter will set a flag
如果我们基本上还没有开始一次遭遇 就会允许我们移动
if we have not started an encounter basically and will allow us to move.
如果我们已经检查了一次相遇 它会的
And if we have checked for an encounter, it will,
或者 如果我们触发了一次遭遇 它就会推入check ForEncount
or if we have triggered an encounter, it will push in checkForEncounter,
它实际上会将战斗状态推送到堆栈上
it'll actually push a battle state onto the stack.
所以check ForEncount基本上就是做我们之前说过的事情
So checkForEncounter just basically does what we said before.
如果是草层 因为我们有两层
If the grass layer, because we have two layers,
对 我们有基层和草层
right, we have the base layer and the grass layer.
因此 如果yx所在的yx处的层是实体map x和map y
So if the layer at yx where yx is are entities map x and map y.
如果它的ID等于高草
If the ID of that is equal to tall grass,
我们只有一个全局常量表 叫做
and we have just a global constant table called
磁贴ID 其中包含所有这些ID
Tile IDs, which has all these IDs.
且math.随机性10等于1 OK 将实体状态改为空闲
And math.random10 is equal to 1, OK, change the entity state to idle,
所以不要让他们继续走下去
so don't let them keep walking.
暂停现场音乐 而不是停止
Pause the field music rather than stopping,
这样 当我们稍后回到赛场并按下Play键时
so that way when we come back to the field later and we press play,
它将处于与以前完全相同的位置
it will be at the exact point that it was before.
引发了战斗音乐 然后 我们已经看到了 在状态中褪色
Triggered the battle music, and then, we've seen this already, fade in state,
推送到堆栈 对吗？
push to the stack, right?
所以超过一秒钟 我们就会褪色成白色
So over one second, we're going to fade to white.
所以这将会有音乐开始的效果
So this will have the effect of the music starting,
但我们马上就会褪色成白色 这
but we're fading to white right away, which
与大多数RPG的操作方式非常相似
is very sort of similar to how most RPGs do it.
然后我们有我们的回调函数 它
And then we have our callback function, which
会在淡入状态结束后立即执行 对吗？
will execute as soon as the fade in state's done, right?
在这种情况下 推向战斗状态
In this case, push to battle state.
战斗状态需要一个实体 而实体
Battle state takes an entity, and the entity
有我们所有的精灵宝可梦信息 那是
has all of our Pokemon information, that's
为什么我们要让它进入战斗状态
why we're passing that into the battle state.
所以战斗状态可以说 哦 你有什么精灵宝可梦？
So the battle state can say, oh, what Pokemon do you have?
好的 我会看着你的派对说 好的 你的第一个精灵宝可梦
OK, I'll be able to look at your party and say, OK, your first Pokemon
这是不是把他送上战场 等等 对不对？
is this, send him out to battle, et cetera, right?
最后 推入淡出状态 对
And then lastly, push a fade out state, right,
因为现在我们已经将战斗状态置于播放状态之上
because now we've got the battle state on top of the play state,
但我们想淡入其中 对吗？
but we want to fade into it, right?
所以我们将淡出 我们将把战斗状态放在第一位
So we're going to fade, we're going to put the battle state first,
然后因为我们使用的是堆栈 所以我们
and then because we're using a stack, we're
把命运置于最上面的状态 然后淡出
going to put the fate out state on top of that, and then fade out to that,
把它从堆栈上弹出来
pop that off the stack.
然后我们就有了我们刚刚推动的战斗状态 对吗？
And then we have our battle state that we just pushed, right?
然后是自己 遭遇基金会在这里设定
And then self.encounterFound get's set here.
这就是创造一次相遇 随机检查
And that's creating an encounter, checking randomly,
把正确的事情推到堆栈下 战斗状态
pushing the right things under the stack, battle state,
淡出状态 淡入 淡出
fade state, fade in, fade out.
然后你就可以走了
And then you're set to go.
所以这实际上就是--
So that's effectively what the--
在RPG中 它被称为场对战斗或遭遇状态
it's known in RPGs as the field versus the battle or encounter state.
尽管我们在这里称之为Play State 但我们已经离开了赛场
Even though we're calling it play state here, we've left the field,
在这一点上 我们已经进入了战斗
we've gone into the battle at this point.
所以现在我们基本上已经看到了一切
And so now we've seen basically everything
这个领域必须为我们提供
that the field has to offer us.
我们已经报道了所有与此相关的内容
And we've covered everything that's relevant there.
所以我们现在休息5到10分钟
So we're going to take a break now for five to 10 minutes,
当我们休息回来的时候
and then when we get back from the break,
我们将讨论图形用户界面元素、面板、文本框、
we'll talk about GUI elements, panels, text boxes,
然后我们将深入研究战斗状态的那种机制
and then we'll dive into the sort of mechanics of the battle state.
好了 欢迎回到第七课 精灵宝可梦
All right, welcome back to lecture 7, Pokemon.
所以在休息之前 我们讨论了比赛状态
So before the break, we talked about the play state,
我们谈到了更重要的州堆栈
we talked about the states stack more importantly,
然后我们讨论了匿名函数是如何
and then we talked about how a anonymous functions are
这是我们如何获得大量异步
sort of the backbone to how we get a lot of this asynchronous
和延迟行为 这在RPG中很常见
and deferred behavior for our game, which is very common in RPGs,
我的意思是 很多类型 很多复杂的类型
and I mean, a lot of genres, a lot of complicated genres of this sort.
像这样的游戏的另一个重要部分是图形用户
Another big key part of games like this are the graphical user
界面 或者简称为GUI
interfaces, or GUIs as they're shortened to.
像屏幕上的面板 标签之类的东西
Things like panels on the screen, things like labels--
可以移动的文本标签 比如列表 文本框 滚动条
text labels that move around, things like lists, text boxes, scroll bars,
你可以变得更疯狂
and you can get a lot crazier with it.
在这节课里 我们主要讨论面板 标签
In this particular lecture, we'll be talking mostly about panels, labels,
文本框和滚动条
text boxes, and scroll bars--
而不是滚动条
progress bars rather, not scroll bars.
但我认为第一个角落
But the sort of the first I think corner--
或者第一种类似keystone的GUI小部件
or the first sort of like keystone GUI widget
我们应该考虑的是陪审团
that we should take into consideration is the panel.
”““那是一个小组 听不见
So a panel is [INAUDIBLE].
如果我们把这个放在一个博弈中
So if we look at this in a game--
就当这是一个面板吧
just pretend this is a panel I guess.
所以这就是一个小组的全部 对吗？
So this is effectively all a panel is, right?
它只是一个长方形
It's just sort of a rectangle.
它让我们可以--如果你在看大多数的用户界面
It allows us to-- if you're looking at most user interfaces,
比如屏幕上的文本框 或者你在Facebook上
like text boxes on your screen, or if you're on Facebook
你看到的几乎是任何东西 比如你的小信息
and you're looking at almost anything, like your little message
窗户 很多这些东西在最核心的地方 最底层
window, a lot of those things at the very core, the very bottom,
基础部分只是一个面板
the foundational part is just a panel.
那么 有没有人猜到在Love 2D中 我们如何制作一个简单的面板？
So any guesses to how in Love2D, we can make a simple panel?
观众：两个不同颜色的长方形
AUDIENCE: Two rectangles of different colors.
两个不同颜色的长方形
SPEAKER 1: Two rectangles of different colors,
这就是我们最终的结果
that's exactly what we end up doing.
这就是我们制作面板的有效方法
So that's effectively how we can make a panel.
还有另一种制作面板的方法 但我们不会在这节课上做
There's another way of making a panel, which we won't do in this lecture,
但它叫做
but it's called--
我们把它作为一个叫做九补丁的结构
we use as a construct called a nine patch.
所以九号补丁是...
So a nine patch is--
想象一下这张小图片 它的大小任意
imagine taking this little image here, and it's of some arbitrary size,
但它很小
but it's very small.
这和很多游戏
And this is very similar to how a lot of games
实现了他们的面板或图形用户
implemented their panels or their graphical user
在80年代和90年代 我的意思是 到今天为止 很多游戏的界面
interfaces back in the 80s and 90s, I mean, to a lot of games till this day.
但回到硬件基本上是基于瓦片的时候
But back when hardware was fundamentally tile based,
你可以把这样的一张图片 分成九块
you could take a image like this, split it up into nine pieces--
九补丁是这个术语的来源
nine patch is where the terminology comes from.
回忆一下 这和我们建造塞尔达传说中的地牢有点类似
And sort of similar to how we actually constructed the Zelda dungeon, recall,
你有角块 然后是顶部 底部 右侧和左侧
where you have corner pieces, and then a top, bottom, right, and left side.
你只要把这些一层一层地铺上
You just layer this, one of each of these,
第一个 右边 角块
first off, right, of the corner pieces.
然后你需要多少就多少
And then however many you need of these on the sides
来创造这个矩形 对吧
to create this rectangle, right?
想象一下我们创造了
So imagine we've created--
这些都是 如果我们能把它们想象成一堆瓷砖 对吧？
these are all, if we can visualize these as being a bunch of tiles, right?
想象一下我们把这些角块
So just imagine that we've taken these corner pieces,
这些是角上的碎片 我们每个都取了一个
these are the corner pieces, we've taken one of each of those.
然后我们把这些边片 画一堆
And then we take these side pieces, and we just like draw a bunch of them
那样的
like that.
然后我们把这个中心装饰品 然后我们
And then we take this centerpiece, and then we
可以将它分层 或者平铺几次 或者只是拉伸它
can either layer it, or tile it a bunch of times, or just stretch it.
拉伸它会带来一系列的好处
And stretching it has a bunch of nice bonuses associated with it depending
关于你如何设置你的过滤器模式 love.graphics.setdefaultfilter
on how you've set your filter mode, love.graphics.setdefaultfilter,
如果将其设置为“双线性”与“最接近”
if you set it to bilinear versus nearest,
你可以得到一个很好的渐变
you can actually get a nice gradient.
如果你把它设置为最近的 你会得到一个很好的像素化的外观
And if you set it to nearest, you get a nice pixelated look.
但是你会经常看到这一点 Unity对此有很好的支持
But you'll see this often, and Unity has nice support for this.
拍一张可能比你想象的更复杂的照片
Take an image that has maybe more complicated than you could
只需要两个长方形 对吧
get with just two rectangles, right?
一些有设计的东西 也许是渐变色 实际上
Something that actually has a design and maybe a gradient color, and actually
层
layer--
我的意思是 创建一个任意大小的文本框来满足您的需要
I mean, create a arbitrarily sized text box to fit your needs.
如果这些甚至不是增量或无论你的瓷砖大小
And if these aren't even increments or whatever your tile size
是在你的9补丁 你可以只规模的顶部 底部 左侧和右侧
is on your 9 patch, you could just scale the top, bottom, left, and right side
也是为了保持它的比例 中心装饰
as well just to keep it scaled, the centerpiece.
所以这就说得通了
So does that makes sense.
这是很常见的 我们不会在我们的课程中使用它
So this is common, we won't be using that in our lecture,
但这是很多图形用户界面设计中非常、非常常见的一部分
but it's a very, very common piece to a lot of graphical user interface design.
在许多游戏中 如果你对游戏开发有更多的了解 你会看到很多这样的游戏
In a lot of games, you'll see it a lot if you get more into game development,
所以这绝对值得一谈
so it's definitely worth talking about.
我们今天要讨论的另一个部分是文本框
Another piece that we'll be talking about today is the text box.
所以我的意思是 关于文本框是什么
So I mean, what's a guess as to what the text box,
我们如何实现文本框 以及我们将如何实现文本框？
how we can implement a text box, and how we will implement a text box?
那么 我们可以从什么基础工作开始呢？
So what foundational piece can we start with?
我们已经有了--是吗？
We already have-- yeah?
观众：你只要用爱的印记就行了
AUDIENCE: You just put use the love print
其中一个盒子上方的屏幕上
to the screen over one of those boxes.
演讲者1：准确地说 就是在其中一个盒子上方的屏幕上印上爱的印记
SPEAKER 1: So use the love print to the screen over one of the boxes, exactly.
是啊
Yep.
所以维护一个文本项目的列表 对 文本
So maintain a list of text items, right, text.
然后只需将它们绘制在面板内 就会有一个文本框
And then just draw them inside a panel, and there's a text box.
你已经接受了两个想法 并将它们混合在一起
You've taken two ideas, and sort of mix them together.
精选是一回事
A selection is kind of the same thing.
这是唯一的不同之处 就是有一个选择--
It's a the only difference being that with a selection--
因此 如果我们想一想 选择是另一回事
so a selection is another thing if we think about,
例如 菜单中我们有战斗 像奔跑一样
for example a menu where we have fight, and like run,
它可能是在一个更充实的游戏中 我们有一个项目的东西
and it may be in a more fleshed out game, we have like an item thing,
对吗？
right?
所以这是一份有效的菜单
So that's a menu effectively.
它与我们在文本框中得到的非常相似
It is very similar to what we get with a text box,
但它有一系列的元素 战斗 物品 奔跑
but it's got a set of ingredients here, fight, item, run,
它们没有设置为换行 它们不是一个连续的文本集
which they aren't set to wrap, they're not one like contiguous set of text.
这只是一堆东西
It's just a bunch of items.
精选的好处是你可以
And then nice thing about a selection is that you can
在你的选择上有一个光标 对吗？
have a cursor on your selection, right?
然后我们需要联想到什么 比如
And then what do we need to associate with like, for example,
如果我们想让这件事真正起作用
if we want this to actually do something,
如果我们想一想我们到目前为止所做的事情
and if we think about what we've been doing so far,
我们如何着手实现功能
how do we go about implementing functionality
有这样的选择吗？
with a selection like this?
比如 在我们的选择中 哪些条目需要与每个条目相关联？
Like what needs to get associated with each of those entries in our selection?
回调函数 对吗？
Callback function, right?
就像我们处理其他一切一样
Just as we've done with everything else.
如果你这里有一个战斗物品 每一个 如果我们考虑到选择
If you have a fight item here, each of these, if we think of the selection
因为这只是我们所看到的这一部分
as being just this part of what we're looking at,
对 因为这个背景部分只是一个面板 我们不在乎这个
right, because this background part is just a panel, we don't care about that.
目前我们关心的是选择
We care about the selection at the moment.
选择的是项目和箭头 对吗？
The selection is the items and the arrow, right?
正如我们将在作业中看到的 你的目标实际上
When as we'll see in the assignment, your goal will actually
接受选择并去掉箭头功能
be to take selection and get rid of the arrow functionality,
因为对于这个任务 你不需要
because for the assignment, you don't need
或者想要激活选择 激活光标
or want to have a selection active, a cursor active.
你只想要一份物品清单
You just want a list of things.
但根据光标指向的内容以及我们按回车键之类的
But based on what the cursor is pointing at and when we press Enter or whatnot,
我们应该为所选内容编制索引 然后
we should index into the selection, and then
执行与这些项中的每一项关联的回调
execute a callback that's associated with each of these items.
这就是我们可以从选择中提取行为的方法
And that's how we can get behavior out of the selection,
而不仅仅是我们呈现在屏幕上的东西的列表
rather than just being a list of things that we render to the screen.
如果我们打架了 我们按了Enter 这是一个回调
If we have fight, and we click Enter, a callback
设置为可能将某个状态推送到堆栈上 该堆栈
is set to maybe push a state onto the stack that
会在屏幕上引发两个实体之间的互动 对吗？
will trigger an interaction between the two entities on the screen, right?
第一个会攻击第二个
The first one will attack the second one,
第二个会攻击第一个
the second one will attack the first one.
这是它自己的一组异步状态 它们做着自己的事情
And that's sort of its own asynchronous set of states that do its own thing,
但它是通过一个匿名函数启动的
but it's kicked off via an anonymous function
我们都和这些东西联系在一起了 对吗？
that we've associated with each of these things, right?
一个项推送另一个状态 这类似于项的迷你状态 然后您
An item pushes another state, which is like an item mini state, where then you
打开一套全新的菜单 您可以查看您的所有项目
open up a brand new set of menus that you can look through all your items,
每一项都有一个与之关联的回调 对吗？
and each of those items has a callback associated with it, right?
您的药水有关联的回调
Your potion has a callback associated with it
这就是说 当我点击这个时 默认情况下
that says, when I click on this, either by default,
只要恢复我的激活的精灵宝可梦的惠普
just restore the HP of my active Pokemon,
或者让我来选择恢复的对象
or let me choose who to restore.
因此 推送另一个状态 就像选择一个精灵宝可梦
So therefore, push another state, which is like a select Pokemon
屏幕上有它自己的一组与每个回调相关联的回调
screen with its own set of callbacks associated with each of those.
它只是为了得到所有这种复杂的行为
It's just in order to get all of this sort of complicated behavior
这是你需要的 它最终真的只是推动各州
that you need to, it's really ultimately just pushing states
并将回调函数添加到所有这些不同的选项
and adding callback functions to all of these different options
你可以选择
that you can select.
然后跑 推一个淡入淡出状态 然后弹出这个状态
And then run, push a fade state, and then pop this state,
然后推入淡出状态
and then push a fade out state.
这就是我们所做的一切
And that's really all we're doing.
下面我们来看看所有这些图形用户界面小部件
And so this look at all of these GUI widgets
这只是一个概念性的外观 但我们很快就会看到
here is just sort of a conceptual look, but we'll take a look very shortly
在一些实际的实现中
at some actual implementation.
最后一个我想看的是进度条
The last one that I want to look at is the progress bar.
以进度条为例 我们的惠普
So a progress bar for example, the HP that we've
在实际战斗中看到的 当我们受到伤害时 它从右到右
seen in the actual battle where when we take damage, it goes from right to
左边
left.
有没有人猜测我们是如何实现进度条的？
Any guesses as to how we've implemented a progress bar?
什么事 托尼？
Yes, Tony?
观众：再一次 两个长方形
AUDIENCE: Once again, two rectangles.
演讲者1：两个长方形 没错
SPEAKER 1: Two rectangles, yes, exactly.
一个 然后是Love2D中关于矩形的好事情
One, and then the nice thing about rectangles in Love2D
您可以将它们的边缘设置为圆角或不圆角
is you can set the edges on them to be rounded or not
通过可选参数
via an optional parameter.
所以没有比矩形更复杂的东西
So without anything more complicated than a rectangle
我们可以创造出这种近乎椭圆形的进程
we can just create these sort of almost ellipsoid progress
条形图 非常简单的进度条
bars, very simple progress bars.
一个是红色的 对 红色是背景
Ones the red, right, the red that's the background.
然后画出轮廓 黑色
And then ones the outline, the black.
并且其中一个被设置为填充第一个参数
And one is set to fill with the first parameter,
其中一个参数设置为与第一个参数成直线
one's set to line with the first parameter.
现在 我们如何开始制作动画
Now how do we go about animating whether or not,
当我们受到伤害时 我们如何激活生命值的下降？
how do we animate the decreasing amount of health when we take damage?
是?
Yes?
观众：在宽度之间
AUDIENCE: Between the width.
扬声器1：正好在宽度之间
SPEAKER 1: Between the width, exactly.
我们要对它做些什么补充？
And what are we tweening it by?
我们要怎么补齐它呢？
How are we tweening it?
我们如何计算我们需要对它进行多少补间？
How would we calculate how much we need to tween it?
观众：嗯 你可以让你的宽度和你的健康相抵
AUDIENCE: Well, you could just have your width equal your health remaining.
扬声器1：如果您的宽度设置为等于您剩余的健康
SPEAKER 1: If your width is set to equal your health remaining,
那么你的健康状况可能是10岁
then your health is maybe 10.
你想要你的健康条有100个像素
And you want your health bar to be like 100 pixels
龙 这是怎么回事 但工作？
long, how is that going to work though?
观众：乘
AUDIENCE: Multiply it.
你可以乘它 但如果你
SPEAKER 1: You could multiply it, but if you
知道进度条的宽度
know the width that you want your progress bar to be,
你可以用宽度乘以最大值的比率
you can just multiply the width by the ratio of the max
你的HP值 或者抱歉 你当前HP与最大HP的比率
value of your HP, or sorry, the ratio of your current HP over your max HP,
对吧？
right?
所以如果你少了--如果你有50 HP 你少了5 HP
So if you're missing-- if you have 50 HP, and you're missing 5 HP,
你的比率是45/50
your ratio is 45 over 50.
如果你把它乘以宽度 你就得到了精确的宽度
And if you multiply that by your width, you get the exact amount of width
不管你想让酒吧有多宽
that you need regardless of how wide you want the bar to be,
如果你想要1,000像素 或者50像素
if you want to be 1,000 pixels, if you want it to be 50 pixels,
只要你把当前健康值乘以最大健康值乘以宽度
as long as you multiply current health over max health times the width,
无论如何你都会得到那个比率
you'll get that ratio no matter what.
这有道理吗
Does that makes sense?
酷了
Cool.
这就是我们看到的所有GUI小部件 它们是如何排序的
So that's a look at all the GUI widgets that we're looking at, how they sort
与我们正在做的事情有关
relate to what we're doing.
我们将在这里看看它们的实现
We'll take a look at their implementation here.
所以我要打开面板
So I'm going to go ahead and open up the panel.
我会讲得稍微快一点
And I'm going to move a little bit quickly
所以我们可以进入战斗的核心
so we can get into sort of the meat of the battle here.
面板就像我们之前说的 只有两个矩形 对吧？
The panel is as we've said before just two rectangles, right?
它在一个高度内取xy
It takes in an xy within a height.
然后我们画两个矩形
And then we would just draw two rectangles.
一个比另一个大
One is larger than the other.
底部矩形略大于顶部矩形
The bottom rectangle is slightly larger than the top rectangle.
第一个矩形是白色的
So the first rectangle gets drawn and it's whitish.
然后...抱歉抱歉
And then-- oh, I'm sorry, sorry about that.
我们在一个高度内有一个xy
We have a xy within a height.
然后我们在屏幕上画两个矩形
And then we're drawing two rectangles to the screen.
我们有一个背景矩形 它首先被绘制出来
We have the background rectangle, which is drawn first,
也就是面板的整个xy宽度和高度
which is going to be the full xy width and height of the panel.
然后我们用白色画出来 然后画
And then we're going to draw that at a white color, and then draw--
在这个游戏中 我们用同样的颜色画所有的东西
in the context of this game-- we're drawing everything at the same color,
但我们可以改变颜色
but we can change the color.
如果我们想让它参数化 我们可以这么做
If we wanted to parameterize it, we could do that.
我们可以设置 我们可以在构造函数中有一个颜色选项
We could set, we could have a color option here in the constructor.
我们不是这样做的 我们只是把所有东西都画成同样的颜色
We're not doing that, we're just drawing everything the same color.
但这就是你获得定制菜单的方式
But that's how you would get like customized menus,
有些RPG可以让你这么做
some RPGs let you do that.
然后我们在这里做的是我们只是在一个稍微小一点的范围内
And then what we're doing here is we're just within a small slightly smaller
边界
boundary.
所以在x和y上只小了两个像素
So just two pixels smaller on the x and y.
你要画第二个矩形的地方
Where you are going to draw the second rectangle,
这是一种灰色的深色
which is a kind of dark shade of gray.
这是一个小组 这就是小组的全部
And that is a panel, that is all panel is.
然后我们可以只有一个名为
And then we could just have a function called
切换 将其设置为可见或不可见
toggle, which sets it to visible or not visible.
如果它是可见的 就把它扔掉 如果它是可见的 对不起 就画出来
And if it's visible, get rid of it, or if it's visible, sorry, draw it.
否则 在渲染时不要绘制任何内容
Otherwise, don't draw anything when it gets rendered.
简而言之 这就是一个面板
So that's a panel in a nutshell.
有什么问题吗？
Any questions?
凉爽的
Cool.
所以接下来我们要看的是文本框
So the next thing that we should look at is the text box.
所以有一个文本框--
So a text box--
因此 文本框比面板稍微复杂一些
so the text box is a little bit more complicated than a panel.
简而言之 文本框需要接受一些任意的文本正文
A text box in a nutshell needs to take in some arbitrary body of text,
它需要根据文本框的宽度对其进行分割
and it needs to chop it up based on how wide your text box is.
如果它超过了文本框的高度
And if it surpasses the height of your text box,
对 理想情况下 你应该翻页你的文字 这样你就可以按空格键
right, ideally, you should page your text so that you can press Space bar,
输入并浏览多页文本 直到用完所有文本
Enter and go through pages of text until you've exhausted all of your text.
最后再按一次Enter键 就可以去掉那个文本框
And you press Enter one last time, and you get rid of that text box.
所以我们这里有一个面板 我们有XY的宽度和高度
And so we have a panel here, which we have an xy width and height
在文本框的构造函数中
in our constructor for the text box.
我们也有我们的文本
And we have our text as well.
然后我们有一个字体 如果我们想要明确地决定
And then we have a font if we want to explicitly decide
我们要使用的字体
what font we want to use.
在这种情况下 或者在逃亡中 我们会说
In this case, or at large, we're going to say
我们实例化一个XY宽度和高度的面板 不要太花哨
that we instantiate a panel at xy width and height, nothing too fancy.
然后是幻想的部分 稍微复杂的部分
And then the fancyish part, the slightly more complicated part
在这里的第20行 我们说 下划线
is here on line 20 where we say, underscore
Self.extChucks得到的是self.font、getWrap、self.text、self.width减去12
self.textChucks gets self.font, getWrap, self.text, self.width minus 12.
有谁知道这个函数是做什么的 或者想猜一猜？
So anybody know what this function does or want to take a guess?
是?
Yes?
观众：这就是你说的那个页面吗？
AUDIENCE: Is that the page thing you were talking about?
演讲者1：没错 这就是文本的分页
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, it's the paging of the text.
更确切地说是文本的组块
Is the chunking of the text rather.
不是文本的分页 而是文本的组块 这
Not the paging of the text, so much as is the chunking of the text, which
我们将使用来对文本进行分页
we will use to page the text.
所以我们取了一些你知道的任意大的文本
So we take some you know arbitrarily large body of text,
它可以像我们想要的那样大 并且给定--
it can be as large as we want it to be, and given--
这实际上是Love2D字体对象的一个函数
this is actually a function of to Love2D font object.
这是Love2D给我们的
So this is given to us from Love2D.
GET WRAP将返回两个值 第二个值
Get wrap will return two values, the second of which
是主体大体被分成的所有文本片段
is all of the pieces of text that the main big body is divided into
根据宽度
based on the width.
所以这个自身宽度是负12 这就是宽度
So this self.width of minus 12, that's how wide
它将把我们的文本分成多个块
it's going to divide our text into chunks of up to,
它可能略小于 因为它将它分开
it could be slightly smaller than, because it divides it
基于这个词
based on the word.
但是 任何文本都不会超过自身宽度减去12宽度
But no piece of text will ever exceed self.width minus 12 width.
这将允许我们在文本中呈现几行文本
And this will allow us to then render several lines of text within our text
盒子 他们永远不会超过边界 对吗？
box, and they will never exceed the boundary, right?
因此 分页功能实际上将在下一块中实现
And so the paging functionality is actually in next chunks.
因此 我们在[？]的末尾称自己为Next针织？]功能
So we call self next here at the end of [? knitt ?] function.
然后Self下一步基本上检查一下 好的 我们在课文的末尾吗？
And then self next basically checks to see, OK, are we at the end of the text?
如果是 那么我们将不会显示任何文本
If we are, then we're not going to display any text,
我们要把窗户关上
and we're going to close the window.
我们要关闭电池板
We're going to close the panel.
但如果我们没有在文本的末尾 就像我们仍然得到文本一样
But if we are not at the end of the text, like we still get text left,
我们想要做的是新桌子
what we want to do is new table.
然后我们将进行最多三次迭代
And then we're going to, up to three iterations,
我们跟踪我们在块中的位置 对吗？
we keep track of where we are in our chunks, right?
我们得到的文本块等于所有这些块 对吧
We get self.text chunks equal to all of those chunks, right.
这可能是一个任意的数字
And that could be an arbitrary number.
可能只有一块 可能有30块 对吧？
It can be only one chunk, there could be like 30 chunks, right?
我们需要一个柜台来记录我们在哪里
We need a counter to keep track of where we
都是基于我们所在的页面 对吧
are in terms of like based on what page we're on, right,
以及到目前为止我们在屏幕上渲染了多少行
and however many lines we rendered to the screen thus far.
所以从i开始 我得到了块计数器
So starting at I, and I get's chunk counter,
并且块计数器将递增3
and chunk counter will get incremented by three
每次我们调用下一块 也就是每一页
every time we call next chunks, which is every page.
我们也可以很容易地将这一页称为下一页
We could have easily just called this next page as well.
它将插入到Chchks表中
It's going to insert into that chunks table
我们刚刚创建的 self.extChucks at i
that we just created, self.textChucks at i.
一旦我们达到了区块总数
And once we've reached the number of chunks total
我们从Get WRAP返回的 我们将标记文本结束
that we returned from get wrap, we're going to flag end of text
是真的 然后我们会把它退回
as being true, and then we're going to return it.
因此 最终 我们将会
And so what this will do is, eventually, we're
将等于我们从Font Get WRAP中获得的区块数量
going to be equal to the number of chunks that we got from font get wrap,
对吗？
right?
一旦我们做到了 这将是Next的信号
And once we are, that will signal with next
是时候关闭文本框了 因为文本结束了
that it's time to close the text box, because end of text
将在最后一个分块过程结束时设置为True
will have been set to true at the end of that last chunking process.
然后我们可以看到 当我们更新文本框时
And then we can see here, when we update text box,
当它在堆栈的顶部时
and that whenever it's on the top of the stack,
记住 我们要找的是空格键或回车键
remember, we're looking for a Space or an Enter press,
然后我们就给赛尔夫打个电话
and then we just call self next.
这将产生最终关闭我们的文本框的效果
And that will have the effect of eventually closing our text box.
然后是封闭式召回 我们之前看过 我们检查过
And then is closed recall, we looked at that earlier, we checked
要查看文本框是否关闭？
to see it is the text box closed?
这只是我们在这里设置的一面旗帜
And that's just a flag that we set here.
然后出于渲染的目的 我们首先渲染面板
And then for rendering purposes, we render the panel first.
然后对于我们的每个展示块 我们最多只有三个
And then for each of our displaying chunks, so we only have up to three
一次显示块 这由下一个块函数设置
displaying chunks at one time, which gets set by the next chunks function.
我们只需将其打印到屏幕上 使用i作为y的乘数
We just print that to the screen using i as a multiplier on our y.
这将产生两到三条线 i i+1 i+2
And so that will render up two or three lines, i, i plus 1, i plus 2.
对文本框的工作原理有任何疑问吗？
Any questions as to how the text box works?
当然 这比小组的工作要多一点
It's a little more work than the panel for sure,
但这相当直截了当
but it's fairly straightforward.
我们只是在保存一堆文字信息的清单
We're just keeping a list of a bunch of text things,
然后我们只是根据文本的宽度对它们进行分块
and then we're just chunking them based on how wide the text
盒子是 它的尺寸
box is, the dimensions thereof.
然后让我们来看看这个精选
And then let's take one look at this selection.
因此 选择基本上就是带有光标的文本项列表 对吗？
So a selection is basically, a list of text items with a cursor, right?
就像我之前说的 当我们看着那边的屏幕时
And as I said before when we were looking at the screen over there,
每个文本项都有一个文本值和一个回调函数
each of those text items has a text value and a callback function.
回调函数使我们能够
And the callback function is what allows us
要将行为分配给该选择对象 而不仅仅是显示内容
to assign behavior to this selection object beyond just displaying things,
对吗？
right?
因为当你有一个菜单 当你有一个选择
Because when you have a menu, when you have a selection
你选择了一些东西 你希望行为发生 对吗？
and you select something, you want behavior to happen, right?
因此 这些条目中的每一个inde.Items都会有一个回调函数
So each of these items indef.items will expect to have a callback function.
然后在这里 当我们更新选择时 我们正在做的是
And then here, when we update the selection, what we're doing
我们正在更新我们当前选择的内容 这就是
is we're updating whatever our current selection is, which is just
介于1和该选择中的项目数之间的数字 以确保
a number between 1 and the number of items in that selection making sure
如果我们在一 我们去负一 我们回到底部
that if we're at one and we go minus one, that we go back to the bottom.
如果我们按下时处于底部 而我们向上
And if we're at the bottom when we press, and we go up,
我们回到顶端
we go back to the top.
我们演奏声音 可爱 诸如此类的东西
And we play sounds, cutesy, things like that.
然后对于每一个--
And then for each--
对于我们在这里的选择 从一项到多项
and for our selection here, from one to number of items,
我们计算我们需要多少填充物
we calculate how much padding that we need.
然后我们将光标画在我们当前的选择上
And we draw the cursor at our current selection,
然后我们根据i绘制每个项目 不管我们的间隙宽度是多少
and then we draw each item based on i and whatever our gap width is
我们的小组 我们将其分配给小组
of our panel, which we assign it to.
所以我们把小组分成几部分 然后基本上
So we divide our panel up, and then basically just
跟踪当前y的位置并绘制
keep track of where current y is and draw
实际选定内容和光标(如果是
the actual selection and the cursor if that's
将当前选定内容添加到屏幕上
the current selection to the screen.
关于精选的工作原理有什么问题吗？
Any questions as to how a selection sort of works?
请注意 如果我们按下Return 如果我们的选择正在更新
Notice here, if we press Return, if our selection is being updated,
Self.Items at self.CurrentSelection.onSelect
self.items at self.currentSelection.onSelect.
因此 预计该项将具有onSelect函数 该函数
So it's expected that that item will have an onSelect function, which
是回调函数
is that callback function.
好的 最后 我们来看一下菜单
OK, and lastly, we'll take a look at the menu.
然后我们最后来看看这场战斗
And then we'll finally take a look at the battle,
这就是所有的一切都与这一切联系在一起的地方
which is where sort of everything kind of comes together with all of this.
就这么定了
And that'll be it.
然后我们再讨论作业
And then we'll talk about the assignment.
因此 菜单是一个面板和一个选项
So the menu is a panel and a selection together.
这就是这款游戏中菜单背后的主旨
That's the gist behind what a menu is in this game.
你可以把菜单定义为有很多东西
You can define a menu to be a lot of things,
菜单可能会变得更复杂 但在本例中
and you can get a lot more complicated with a menu, but in this example,
在这个实现中 我们只是说菜单是一种选择
in this implementation, we're just saying a menu is a selection
以及一块拼装成一件物品的面板
and a panel put together as one item.
我们在比赛中看到了这一点 如果我们是？]我要运行它
And we've seen it in the game, [? if we're ?] going to run it.
这只是一个文本框
That's just a text box.
去寻找一场战斗
Going to look for a battle.
好了 这是一场战斗
OK, so here's a battle.
这只是底部的一个空面板 普通的面板
That's just an empty panel at the bottom, regular panel,
但现在它是一个文本框
but now it's a text box.
我们将文本框压入堆栈
We push the text box onto the stack.
将另一个文本框推入堆栈
Push another text box onto the stack.
这是一份菜单
And so this is a menu right here.
请注意 其中有一个光标 还有
Notice that there is a cursor and there's
嵌入到面板中的选定内容
a selection embedded within a panel.
其中的每一项 打斗和逃跑
And each of those items, the fight and the run,
它们有一个与之关联的回调
those have a callback associated with them.
战斗回调的目的是触发一个新状态
The purpose of the fight callback is to trigger a new state
其中两个精灵宝可梦在连锁行为中相互异步攻击
where the two Pokemon asynchronously attack each other, in chain behavior
一个接一个
one after the other.
然后Run推动对话 然后推动淡入淡出状态
And then run pushes a dialogue, then pushes a fade state,
然后弹出这两个按钮 然后按下淡出状态
then pops both of them, and then pushes a fade out state
并将我们带回游戏状态
and puts us back to the play state.
所以这实际上就是正在发生的事情 那就是
So that's effectively what's going on and that's
菜单是什么样子的一个例子
an example of what the menu looked like.
这样就有了一个菜单 只是一个选项和一个面板放在一起
And so a menu, just a selection with a panel put together.
当我们绘制菜单时 先绘制面板 然后绘制所选内容
When we draw the menu, we draw the panel and then the selection.
然后当我们更新菜单时 我们只更新选项
And then when we update the menu, we only update the selection,
因为那才是我们所关心的
because that's all we care about.
基本上就是这样
And that's basically it.
所以菜单本身会有一个定义 这个定义
And so the menu itself will get a def, that def
应该有项目 该项目将被传递到选择
should have items, that items will get passed to the selection.
差不多就是这样 就是这样--
That's pretty much, that's it for the--
哦 还有进度条
oh, progress bar as well.
当我们到达实际战斗状态时 我们将查看进度条
We'll look at progress bars when we get to the actual battle state.
现在 让我们来看看几个类和数据结构
So now, let's take a look at a few of the classes and data structures
这与精灵宝可梦本身有关
that are pertinent to the Pokemon themselves.
所以如果你把派对看成是头等舱的话 非常
So if you look at party as are first class, very
简单的类 字面意思就是这个--
simple class, literally just this--
在这一点上 self.pokemon是定义的 pokemon只是一个容器
self.pokemon is def.pokemon is just a container at this point.
你可以拿着这个
You can take this--
我的意思是 即使在我认为是一场完整的比赛中
I mean, even in I think a fully fleshed game,
你真的不需要比这更多的东西了
you wouldn't really need much more than just this.
但是 如果您需要对这个想法进行进一步的扩展
But if you needed to expand upon this idea at all
你知道 保留为派对而存在的元数据
and you know preserve metadata that exists for the party,
这将是一种完美的方式
this would be a perfect way to do it.
实际的口袋妖怪类本身并不比有效的多很多
The actual pokemon class itself is not a whole lot more than effectively
一堆统计数据
a bunch of stats.
这就是RPG的很多特点
And that's a lot of what an RPG is.
这种类型--它主要是数字
This genre is-- it's mostly just numbers.
你只是在把数字和数字进行比较
You're just comparing numbers against numbers
然后加入一卷骰子
and then adding a roll of the dice.
实际上 这就是《地下城与龙》的大部分内容
That's effectively, that's what Dungeons &amp; Dragons, a lot of it is.
那就是--是吗？
And that's-- yes?
观众：储存是不是更有意义？
AUDIENCE: Would it make more sense to store
只需每个级别和初始级别的增量 这样您就可以有更少的变量？
just delta per level and your initial one, so you can have fewer variables?
演讲者1：再说一遍
SPEAKER 1: Say it one more time.
观众：这不是更有意义吗？
AUDIENCE: Wouldn't it make more sense, instead
存储您的HP和每个级别的所有内容
of storing your HP and everything for each level
要存储每个区域的初始统计数据
to store your initial stats in each area,
以及每一关你会涨多少钱
and how much you would go up per level.
演讲者1：把你增加的钱存起来会更有意义吗？
SPEAKER 1: Would it make more sense to store the amount that you go up
为你的精灵宝可梦每一级？
per level for your Pokemon?
是的 这就是我们正在做的
Yes, that is what we're doing.
所以我们有一个基地--
So we have a base--
在这种情况下 统计数据的拆分是这样的 对吗？
so here's how the split works for the stats in this case, right?
我们有基础HP、基础攻击、基础防御和基础速度
We have base HP, base attack, base defense, and base speed.
1级精灵有--0级精灵
A level 1 Pokemon has-- a level 0 Pokemon
有这个物种的这些统计数据 对吗？
has these stats of this species, right?
每一个竹子或我们选择的任何精灵宝可梦
Every Bamboon or whatever Pokemon that we choose
会有我们分配给它的任何东西作为它的基础HP
will have whatever we've allocated it to be it's base HP,
基地 进攻 基地防御 基地速度
base, attack, base defense, base speed.
然后关于精灵宝可梦和我的意思是 很多RPG
And then the thing about Pokemon and I mean, a lot of RPGs
会做这件事 但我们需要一些方法
will sort of do this thing, but we need some way
以一种必然不确定的方式升级精灵宝可梦
of leveling up the Pokemon in an necessarily non-deterministic way.
就像两只升级的小猪可能有不同的统计数据 对吗？
Like two Piggies that level up may not have the same stats, right?
其中一个的攻击率可能比另一个略高
One might have slightly higher attack than the other,
其中一个人的防御能力可能略高于另一个人
one might have slightly higher defense than the other.
我们使用所谓的静脉注射来完成这项工作 这就是精灵宝可梦本身所做的事情
We do this using what's called an IV, and that's what Pokemon itself does.
它是个人价值的缩写 这是一种
And it's short for individual value, this is sort of
就像你的精灵宝可梦的DNA一样 对吧？
like the DNA of your Pokemon, right?
所以这个HP IV与你的基础攻击、基础速度、基础等等是分开的
So this HP IV is separate from your base attack, base speed, base et cetera.
基本上 每次都会将其与掷骰子进行比较
And this basically, it gets compared against a dice roll every time
你升级了三次
you level up three times.
这就是我对它进行编程的方式 不一定
And this is how I've programmed it, it's not necessarily
精灵宝可梦本身是如何做到这一点的 但你要掷骰子六次
how Pokemon itself does it, but you will roll a dice six times,
或者三次 一到六次 就像正常的死亡一样
or three times, one through six like a normal die.
然后你会看看这个卷曲是否比你的静脉注射更大 对吗？
And you'll look to see if that roll is greater than your IV, right?
或者它会检查你的静脉输液是否小于或等于掷骰子
Or it'll check to see whether your IV is less than or equal to that dice roll.
如果是的话
And if it is--
或者抱歉 如果它大于或等于掷骰子
or sorry, if it's greater than or equal to that dice roll.
如果是 它将为这三个掷骰子将该统计信息加1
And if it is, it will increment that stat by 1 for those three dice rolls.
因此 您最多可以再获得三个 或者您可以增加状态
So you can get up to three more, or you can increase the stat
每级最多三次
by up to three times per level.
但你最多只能打五针
But you can only have an IV up to five.
所以你是在6的情况下滚动 而你偶尔不会滚动6
So you're rolling against a six, and you will occasionally not roll a 6.
它会检查静脉输液是否
It checks to see whether or not the IV is
大于或等于掷骰子
greater than or equal to the dice roll.
如果它不大于或等于事件中的掷骰子
And if it's not greater than or equal to the dice roll in the event
如果是六分 或者静脉注射到四分
that it is a six, or if the IV is up to a four
例如 这意味着五分或六分会反对它
for example, which means a five or six will go against it,
那么它就不会得到统计数据的增长
then it will not get a stat increase.
这是实现这个基于DNA的系统的一种简单方式
And this is a sort of simple way of implementing this DNA based system.
它是随机的 但它是加权的 对吗？
It's randomized, but it's a weighted, right?
如果你有更高的静脉输液 你有更高的可能性
If you have a higher IV, you have a higher likelihood
大于或等于掷骰子的
of being greater than or equal to the dice roll.
这就是我们如何实现统计增加
And so that's how we implement stat increases.
然后我们需要一种方法来跟踪我们的统计数据
And then we need a way of keeping track of what our stats are,
比如我们的实际数据
like our actual stats.
所以我们的实际HP 我们的实际攻击 我们的实际防御
So our actual HP, our actual attack, our actual defense,
和一层一层计算出来的实际速度
and actual speed that's been calculated level by level,
我们需要一种方法来跟踪它
we need a way to keep track of that.
我们需要等级 我们需要当前的XP 然后
We need level, we need our current XP, and then
我们需要我们的经验值
we need our-- and the amount of XP to gain
一级一级地越升越高 就像你在这里看到的
a level, which will get higher and higher per level, as you can see here,
因为它吸收了自我 水平乘以自我 水平
because it takes in the self.level times self.level.
然后乘以5乘以0.75
And then it multiplies that by five times 0.75.
现在的HP
And then your current HP.
所以我们并不是一层一层地存储我们的价值
So we're really not storing our value level by level,
我们需要基地 因为我们需要知道我们的基地是什么
we need the base because we need to know what our base was.
我的意思是 我们可以有效地全局引用这些变量
I mean, we could effectively globally reference these variables,
但在这一点上 效率提升很小
but it's minor efficiency gains at that point.
但我们需要静脉注射我们需要...
But we need the IVs and we need the--
我是说 我们需要静脉注射的参考资料 我们需要基础HP的参考资料
I mean, we need a reference to the IVs, we need a reference to the base HP,
我们需要跟踪我们的实际数据
and we need to keep track of whatever our actual stats are,
然后我们现在的HP总是 因为我们现在的HP
and then our current HP always, because our current HP
可能与我们的实际HP不同
can differ from our actual HP.
在实际的游戏中 你可以有你的进攻 防守
And in the actual game, you can have your attack, defense,
和速度也会随着比赛而变化 因为你
and speed also vary match by match, because you
降低你的速度 降低你的攻击
have moves that lower your speed, lower your attack,
降低你的防御等等
lower your defense, et cetera.
在这种情况下 我们还没有实现这一点
In this case, we haven't implemented that,
所以我们没有当前的攻击和防御
so we don't have a current attack, current defense.
但是在一个更完整的实现中 你会有这样的事情
But in a more complete implementation, you would have that sort of thing.
这算是回答了你的问题吗
Does that sort of answer your question?
这是徒劳的吗？
Is that in the right vain?
好的.
OK.
这是升级代码
And so here's the level up code.
就像我说的 掷三次骰子 一比三
So like I said, three dice rolls, one to three.
如果6小于或等于IV 那么它可能是6 在这种情况下
If six is less than or equal to our IV, so it could be a six, in which case,
它将大于最大IV可能的值
it would be greater than what are max IV could possibly be.
静脉注射的范围从1到5 但如果它小于或等于静脉注射
IVs range from one to five, but if it's less than or equal to that IV,
那我们就认为这是统计学上的增长
then we're going to consider that a stat increase.
这是一个加权的奇数 用来确定我们是否得到统计数据的提升
It's a weighted odd to determine whether or not we get a stat boost.
它对每个统计数据都这样做 然后返回所有增加的数据
And it does this for every stat, and then it returns all of the increases.
这是相关的 这一行95表示惠普的收益增加
And this is relevant, this line 95 for a return HP increase,
回击增加进攻 增加防守
return attack increase, defense increase.
这将与作业7相关 因为您的目标是
This will be relevant for assignment 7, because your goal is
在战斗中将这些增加并实际显示给这个用户
to take these increases and actually display them to this user in the battle
说明他或她什么时候取得胜利
state when he gets a victory, or he or she gets a victory
并且已经达到了一个级别
and has gained a level.
您将显示一个菜单 其中的选项包含所有这些内容
You will display a menu with a selection that has all of these things,
你需要这个值
and you'll need this value.
所以它在这里返回这些值 您将以任何方式调用此函数
So it returns these values here, and you'll be calling this function any way
从你的战斗状态统计数据升级
from your battle state stats level up.
或者我们将调用Level Up 它返回self stats Level Up
Or we'll be calling level up rather, which returns self stats level up.
这就是精灵宝可梦的全部
And that's all a Pokemon is.
它实际上主要是一种数据结构
It's effectively mostly a data structure.
我们在战斗中用它来有效地来回掷骰子
And we use this in our battles to throw dice effectively back and forth,
有胜利者和失败者 然后通过这种方式获得经验值和增益等级
and have a victor and a loser, and then gain XP and gain levels that way.
那么 关于Pokemon对象类是如何工作的 有什么问题吗？
So any questions as to how a Pokemon object class works?
凉爽的
Cool.
我们将快速了解一下实际定义是什么样子
We'll take a quick look at what the actual definitions look like,
你大概可以猜到
which you can probably take a guess.
这很简单 只是关键的名字
It's very simple, just key names.
然后我们有真正的名字 我们有精灵的名字
And then we have the actual name, we have the sprite names,
我们有HP 攻击 防御--
we have the HP, attack, defense--
所有被放入实际物体中的东西
all the things that get put into the actual object,
它们需要在定义中被引用
they need a reference to in the definitions.
所以精灵宝可梦最终只是这样 他们
And so Pokemon ultimately are just this, they're
就是数据 对 这就是我们在上一节课中谈到的 数据
just data, right, which is what we talked about in a prior lecture, data
驱动设计
driven design.
你能拿到的口袋妖怪就越多
The more you can take all of your Pokemon
把它们做成精灵宝可梦或任何东西
and make them into, or anything, Pokemon or any object,
并将其转换为易于编写的数据结构
and turn it into an easy to write data structure like this,
您就越容易添加更多内容
the easier it is for you to add more.
我们可以很容易地补充说 创建150个这样的设备不会花太长时间
We could easily add, it wouldn't take too long to create 150 of these.
我是说 他们不会那么有趣的
I mean, they wouldn't be all that interesting,
因为我们还没有实施行动
because we don't have moves implemented yet.
但在一个理想的世界里 我们会找到一种方法来将移动也建模为数据
But in an ideal world, we'd find a way to also model moves as data,
因此 您可以将移动链接到您的数据结构
and therefore, you can just link moves to your data structure,
像这样给你的精灵宝可梦对象
to your Pokemon object like this.
是的 托尼 你有问题吗？
Yes Tony, did you have a question?
听众：嗯 我只是想提一下这个悖论
AUDIENCE: Well, I just wanted to mention that the paradox
关于这一点 游戏是非常好的
games are very good about that.
[听不见]
[INAUDIBLE]
演讲者1：哦 就像十字军吗？
SPEAKER 1: Oh, like Crusader Kings?
观众：是的
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
演讲者1：评论是Paradox Games非常好的数据驱动设计
SPEAKER 1: The comment was Paradox Games are very good about data driven design.
我猜你已经查过他们的档案了吧？
I'm assuming you've dug through their files?
观众：在某种程度上 这也只是
AUDIENCE: To some extent, and also it's just
如果你玩他们的游戏一段时间 它无处不在 在一定程度上
if you play their games for awhile, it's everywhere, like to the extent
有时他们会把源代码放在维基上
that sometimes on the Wiki, they put the source code up.
演讲者1：哦 是的
SPEAKER 1: Oh, yeah.
是的 不 这只是一个很好的游戏设计
Yeah, no, it's just good game design.
最终 如果你想--
Ultimately, if you want to--
而且他们的游戏很大 他们有很多内容
and their games are large, they have a lot of content.
如果你想在你的游戏中有很多内容
If you want to have a lot of content in your game,
你需要找到一种方法减轻程序员的负担
you need to find a way to take the burden off the programmer
并把它放在设计师身上 或者至少让
and put it onto the designer, or at least make
这对程序员来说更容易 因为编写源代码
it easier for the programmer, because making source code
整天调试源代码 特别是对于非常复杂的事情
and debugging source code all day long, especially for very complicated things
这不是一件容易的事
is not easy.
而且这最终也不是我们想要做的事情 对吗？
And it's ultimately not a desired thing to do, right?
对我来说 在10行代码中创建一个新生物要容易得多
It's a lot easier for me to whip up a new creature in 10 lines of code
在这里感觉很好 而不是硬编码很多这样的东西
here and feel good about it than hard coding a lot of these sort of things,
对吗？
right?
因此 将尽可能多的数据转换为数据应该是您的最终目标
So shifting as much of it to data as you possibly can should be your end goal.
所以这就是精灵宝可梦防御者的样子
So that's what Pokemon defs look like.
在我们进入实际战斗之前 我们想要
Before we get into the actual battle, we want
来看看什么是战斗精灵
to take a look at what a battle sprite is.
所以战斗精灵就是呈现在屏幕上的东西 对吗？
So a battle sprite is what was rendering onto the screen, right?
所以我们来看看这个
So we take a look here.
那不是战斗精灵 而是几乎是战斗精灵
That's not a battle sprite, but almost a battle sprite.
那只是一种质感
That was just a texture.
因此 如果我们陷入一场战斗 速度缓慢但却是肯定的
So if we get into a battle, slowly but surely.
好了 这些是战斗精灵 它们看起来没什么不同
All right, so these are battle sprites, and they don't look much different
比普通的雪碧还多 而且它们也没有那么多
than a regular sprite, and they're not that much
不同于普通的雪碧
different than a regular sprite.
但它们有一些重要的功能 主要是那些功能
But they have some functionality that's important, mainly that functionality
其中一个是闪烁的 然后是不透明的 对吗？
where one is flashing, and then one was being opaque, right?
因此 为了做到这两点 我们需要存储某种类型的数据
So in order to do both of those things, we need to store some sort of data
在我们的精灵里 对吗？
within our sprite, right?
是?
Yes?
观众：塞尔达的无敌闪光灯
AUDIENCE: Zelda for the invulnerability flashing.
演讲者1：是的 完全正确
SPEAKER 1: Yes, exactly.
我们在塞尔达使用的无懈可击的闪光
For what we used in Zelda for the invulnerability flashing.
对敌人来说 或者我应该说 对被攻击的人来说 是的
For the enemy, or I should say, for whoever is getting attacked, yes.
他们正在存储一面不透明的旗帜
They are getting an opacity flag stored.
他们的对象中存储了一个不透明标志 我们可以对其进行补间
They have an opacity flag stored in their object that we can tween, right,
我们可以随着时间的推移分分合合
we can tween on and off over the course of time.
当塞尔达的实体受到伤害时 我们就是这么做的
That's what we did with the entity in Zelda when it took damage.
我们把它设置为无懈可击 虽然它是无懈可击的
And we set it to invulnerable, and while it was invulnerable,
它在断断续续地闪烁
it was flashing on and off.
但我们不能用闪烁着白色的精灵做到这一点
But we can't necessarily do that with the sprite that's blinking white,
因为这不是真正的白旗 对吧？
because there's not really a like white flag, right?
我们不能只用一面旗帜就把东西变成全白的
We can't make something completely white with just a flag.
这是我们实际上需要使用着色器的东西
That's something that we actually need to use a shader for.
这是一个着色器 我们不会深入到这方面的太多细节
And so a shader, and we're not going to get into too much detail about this,
着色器相当复杂 一开始有点神秘
shaders are pretty complex, a little arcane at first.
但它们实际上是一个小程序
But what they are is effectively a little program that
在你的显卡上运行 当你在画东西的时候 它会看起来
runs on your graphics card, and that looks at when you're drawing something,
它会查看每个像素 具体取决于您使用的着色器类型
it looks at every pixel depending on what kind of shader you're doing.
但为了演示 我们将查看每个像素
But for the sake of this demonstration, we'll look at every pixel
你正在绘制到屏幕上 并执行某种功能
that you're drawing to the screen, and perform some sort of function
并产生一个新的值 对吗？
on that pixel, and produce a new value, right?
这就是你如何让很多疯狂的可怕的事情发生
And this is how you get a lot of really crazy awesome things to happen,
但这可能是相当疯狂的
but it can be pretty insane.
Shader Toy 我认为是一个拥有大量非常酷的--
Shader Toy, I think is the website that has a ton of really cool--
我不会因为我不记得名字就把它拔出来
I'm not going to pull it up now, just 'cause I don't remember the name,
我相信这是着色器玩具
I believe it's shader toy.
有一个网站 人们在那里发布他们编写的所有着色器
There's a website where people post all the shaders that they've written,
你可以看到很多非常疯狂的东西
and you can see a lot of really crazy stuff, things
这是您无法想象的 仅用这样的代码就可以
that you would never imagined were possible with just code like this
有效地 查看像素的位置
effectively, looking at positions of pixels
和[？图片？]在屏幕上什么的
and [? pictures ?] on the screen and whatnot.
但这实际上是一个白色着色器 这个着色器的目标是
But effectively what this does, this is a white shader, the goal of this shader
就是把一个精灵完全变白
is to just turn a sprite completely white.
这就是该着色器的所有目标
That's all the goal of this shader is.
所以它得到了一个叫做白色因子的浮点 哪个[？你会吗？]就这么说吧
So it gets a float called white factor, which [? you'd ?] say here.
那么白人因素实际上就是
And then white factor effectively is just
会被归结为RGB是什么
going to be summed onto whatever the RGB is
当着色器处于活动状态时 我们绘制的任何像素
of that pixel, whatever pixel that we're drawing when the shader is active.
这样做的效果是 如果它等于1 那么就是白色因子
What that has the effect of doing is, white factor, if it's equal to 1.
这是关于着色器和许多这类东西的事情
Here's the thing about shaders and a lot of this stuff,
着色器中的许多数据结构
a lot of the data structures within shaders
基于从0到1的浮点数
are based on floats that are from zero to one.
因此 如果我们将某物的RGB赋给vec 3 即1 即111
So if we assign the RGB of something to a vec 3 that's 1, which is 111,
那将是255,255,255
that's going to be 255, 255, 255.
所以 那个像素RGB是白色的 纯白的 对吧？
Therefore, that pixels RGB is white, pure white, right?
所以我们在这里做的是在我们的战斗精灵上 自己眨眼
And so what we're doing here is on our battle sprite, self.blinking
1或0 记住 这是Lua[？Turnerri？]行动
and one or zero, remember, that's the LUA [? turnerri ?] operations.
所以我们说 如果自我眨眼是真的 那么另一个是零
So we're saying, if self.blinking is true, one else zero.
因此 发送我们的着色器基于任何值本身的白色因素 闪烁
So send our shader white factor based on whatever value self.blinking is.
这将产生着色器获得1或0的效果
And so that will have the effect of the shader getting a one or a zero,
并将1或0加到那个精灵的RGB上
and adding a one or a zero to the RGB of that sprite.
如果闪烁设置为真 则精灵的
And if blinking is set to true, the sprite's
基本上是在255,255,255的每个像素上绘制
going to basically be drawn every pixel at 255, 255, 255.
否则 它将使用该图像的像素值绘制
Otherwise, it'll get drawn with whatever that image's pixel value is
在那个位置
at that position.
这说得通吗？
Does that makes sense?
好的
OK.
语法有点奇怪 但那是
The syntax is a little bit weird, but that's
在此着色器中发生的情况
what's happening here in this shader.
这里有一个我找到着色器的链接
And there's a link here where I found the shader,
但这是一个非常简单的着色器
but it's a very simple, very simple shader,
可能是您可以编写的最简单的着色器之一
probably like one of the simplest shaders you could write.
但这是一个很好的例子 说明了您可以使用着色器做什么 而且非常简单
But it's a great example of what you can do with a shader, and pretty simply.
这很好 因为你可以用纹理坐标做数学运算
And it's nice, because you can take like texture coordinates and do math
以此为基础 或者像素坐标 并在此基础上进行数学运算
based on that, or pixel coordinates and do math based on that.
例如 在您的文件中 您可以像正弦函数一样传入
You can pass in like a sine function for example, in your file,
并使正弦函数对子画面RG或B值执行运算
and have that sine function perform work on like RG or B value of your sprite
做各种很酷的事情
and do all kinds of cool stuff.
它真的很整洁 就像着色器的可能性是无限的
It's really neat, like the possibilities are limitless with shaders.
但这就是我们让它眨眼的方式 因为你
But that's how we get it to blink, because you
除了这个 我不能这么做--
can't do that outside of this--
我是说 可能有一些奇怪的方法也能让它起作用
I mean, there's probably some weird way could get it to work as well,
但这可能是让我们的精灵闪烁白色的最简单的方法
but this is probably the simplest way we can get our sprites blinking white.
所以自我 眨眼只会得到一个计时器 每0.1个或其他什么
And so self.blinking just gets a timer.every0.1 or whatever.
我们将在攻击状态下看到这一点
We'll actually see that in the attack state.
但那会闪到自己 在真与假之间眨眼
But that'll flick to self.blinking between true and false.
它会一次又一次地否定自己
It'll negate itself over and over again.
好了 这就是战斗精灵
All right, so that's the battle sprite.
最后我们要看的是另一个非常简单的类 对手
Last thing we'll look at is another extremely simple class, opponent.
所有的对手就是它有一个政党 仅此而已
All the opponent is is it has a party, that's it.
但在一场全面的比赛中 你的对手
But in a fully fleshed game, your opponent
可能会有一个像训练师一样的精灵
might have a like trainer sprite.
一条信息 它说 就像一个完整的派对
A message that it says, like a full party
精灵宝可梦 当你打败它时 它会给你带来黄金价值
of Pokemon, a gold value that will give you when you defeat it,
各种各样的事情
all kinds of things.
但它在这里只是作为一个简单的说明
But it's here just as a simple illustration.
嗯?
Yeah?
观众：[听不见]用一种方法来应对失败
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] put a method for on defeat
如果你想让它崩溃的话
if you want to maybe have it kind of collapse
房间或类似的东西
the room or something like that.
这将是你可以做的另一件事
That would be another thing that you could do.
演讲者1：哦 一种方法？
SPEAKER 1: Oh, a method?
是的 我们可以把一种方法和一种叫做失败的对手联系起来
Yeah, we can associate a method with an opponent called on defeat,
或者什么都不会做武断的事情 把房间弄塌
or whatnot that will do arbitrary things, collapse the room,
或者是其他原因
or otherwise.
是的 绝对的
Yes, absolutely.
或者甚至推动一个新的状态 就像传送
Or even push a new state, like to like teleport
世界地图上的一个新位置
us to a new location in the world map.
也许我们就像淘汰了精英四人组
Maybe we like cleared the elite four and we
想要传送到喜欢的结束字幕 确切地说
want to get teleported to like the end credits, exactly.
无限的可能性
Limitless possibility.
那么让我们继续下去看看吧 我们还有20分钟的时间
So let's go ahead and take a look now while we have just like 20 more minutes
或者说离开了
or so left.
我们来看看战斗状态 因为这场战斗
We'll take a look at the battle state, because the battle
州和他们所处的州可能是更复杂的一面
state and the states that they're in are probably the more complicated side
这是如何运作的
of how this works.
所以在战斗状态下 我们有一个玩家 我们有一个底部面板 底部面板
So a battle state, we have a player, we have a bottom panel, the bottom panel
因为当我们仅仅为了这一部分而启动州时
for when we start the state just for that part,
但除此之外 我们总是把事情往上推
but otherwise, we're always pushing things onto it.
不管我们是否已经开始战斗 因为当我们逐渐淡出时--
Whether we've started the battle or not, because when we are fading in--
抱歉 是的
sorry, yeah.
因为当我们初始化这个状态时 我们还会将淡出状态添加到它上面
Because when we initialize this state, we also push a fadeout state onto it.
但我们不想触发精灵宝可梦的滑行
But we don't want to trigger the tween of the Pokemon sliding
从左到右 直到该状态被弹出
from left to right until after that state gets popped.
因此 我们在这里有一个标志 它将在第一次更新时设置为真
So we have a flag here, which will get set to true on the very first update
迭代
iteration.
然后 当它设置为真时 我们将
And then when that gets set to true, we'll
实际上 在精灵宝可梦从左到右之间
actually tween the Pokemon going left to right,
并启动所有其他类型的异步进程
and kick off all the other sort of asynchronous processes
在那之后存在的
that exist thereafter.
但让我们再来看看这场战斗 看看发生了什么
But let's look at the battle one more time just to see what's going on.
所以我要一直走下去 直到我投入战斗
So I'm going to walk until I get into a battle.
好了 这是一场战斗
OK, we got a battle.
所以请注意 淡入发生在--
So notice here, the fade in happens as soon as the--
当淡出开始时 滑行就会发生 对吧
the slide in happens as soon as the fade starts, right,
一旦褪色结束 我应该说
as soon as the fade finishes, I should say.
我们会在屏幕上弹出一条信息 对吗？
We get a message popped onto the screen, right?
它说出现了一个狂野的X
It says a wild X appears.
对 那就是敌人的精灵宝可梦
Right, that's the enemy Pokemon.
我们按了回车键
We hit Enter.
把这个关小一点
Turn this down a little bit.
我们按回车键 然后弹出另一个--
We hit Enter, and then we pop another--
将另一个状态推送到堆栈上 另一个战斗消息
push another state onto the stack, another battle message, which
与对话状态非常相似
is very similar to a dialog state.
说加油我们的精灵宝可梦
Says go our Pokemon.
然后我们把菜单推到屏幕上 对吗？
And then we push a menu onto the screen, right?
我们有一个菜单 上面写着 要么战斗 要么逃跑 可供选择
We've got a menu that says, fight or run, a selection.
这是一份菜单 里面有很多选择
It's a menu, which has a selection.
然后 现在 这是堆栈的顶部 对吗？
And then now, this is the top of the stack, right?
所以这是唯一得到输入的东西
So it's the only thing getting input.
其他一切都在它下面渲染 但没有任何东西得到输入
Everything else is rendering beneath it, but nothing's getting input.
因此 我们可以选择要么战斗 要么逃跑
So we have the option to either fight or run.
比方说我们打架
Let's say we fight.
我们战斗 我们现在有了一个新的状态 我们处于攻击状态
We fight, we got a new state now, we're in an attack state.
刚刚发生了几件事
Several things just happened.
那么 一旦我们启动攻击状态 会发生什么？
So what happens as soon as we kick off the attack state?
嗯?
Yeah?
观众：你会看到一个文本框 上面写着 x攻击y
AUDIENCE: You get a text box saying, x attacked y.
演讲者1：是的 所以我们要做的第一件事
SPEAKER 1: Yep, so the first thing we have happened
是一个文本框 上面写着 x攻击y 其中
is, a text box that says, x attacked y, where
要么是我们 要么是对手 因为这是
it could be either us or the opponent, because it's
根据谁的速度更快
based on whoever has the higher speed.
接下来会发生什么呢？
And then what happens next?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
演讲者1：是的 确实如此
SPEAKER 1: Well, it does.
所以让我们现在就来看看它 告诉你
So let's take a look at it right now and tell
告诉我文本框一弹出到底会发生什么
me what exactly happens as soon as the text box pops up.
那么发生在那里的碎片是什么呢？
So what were the pieces that happened there?
观众：闪电侠
AUDIENCE: Flash.
演讲者1：好的 袭击者闪烁白色
SPEAKER 1: OK, so the attacker flashes white,
对 这就是我们看到的着色器
right, which is the shader that we looked at.
这是着色器闪烁和关闭
That's the shader blinking on and off.
有一些计时器显示 每隔0.1秒 闪烁或关闭
There's some timer that says, every 0.1 seconds, blink on or off.
然后会发生什么呢？
And then what happens?
观众：那么伤害就已经造成了 [听不见]..
AUDIENCE: Then the damage is dealt. [INAUDIBLE]..
演讲者1：嗯 伤害已经造成了 是的 但是在视觉上发生了什么
SPEAKER 1: Well, damage is dealt, yes, but what happens visually as soon
当白色闪烁的时候？
as the white blinks?
观众：另一个在眨眼
AUDIENCE: The other one blinks.
扬声器1：另一个在眨眼
SPEAKER 1: The other one blinks.
另一个是什么在眨眼？
What's the other one blinking?
观众：我不确定
AUDIENCE: I'm not sure.
演讲者1：所以这是不透明的 对吗？
SPEAKER 1: So it's opacity, right?
所以请记住 我们正在做的事情与刚才对白人所做的完全相同
So remember, we're doing the exact same thing we just did with that white,
眨眼 但我们每0.1秒就调整一次
with the blinking, but we're tweening every 0.1 seconds
保卫精灵宝可梦的不透明
the opacity of the defending Pokemon.
然后我们就会受到损害
And then we take damage.
那么当我们受到伤害时会发生什么呢？
Then what happens when we take damage?
观众：基本上是相反的
AUDIENCE: The reverse basically.
演讲者1：嗯 当东西受到损坏时 什么会被激活？
SPEAKER 1: Well, what gets animated when the thing takes damage?
我们已经制作了闪烁的动画 我们制作了不透明度的动画
We've animated the blinking, we've animated the opacity.
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
演讲者1：健康条下降了 对吧？
SPEAKER 1: The health bar drops, right?
所以我们把几件事联系在一起
So we're chaining several things together.
我们在链接--首先 我们每0.1秒做一次 共六次
We're chaining-- first, we're doing them every 0.1 seconds for six times,
闪烁白色
blink white.
然后眨眼另一件不透明的东西 对吗？
Then blink the other thing opacity, right?
我们同时也在播放音效
And we're playing sound effects at the same time too,
我们正在为攻击播放音效 为命中播放音效
we're playing a sound effect for the attack, sound effect for the hit.
一旦完成 就在健康吧之间 对吧？
And then once that's finished, tween the health bar, right?
所以我们已经修改了防御精灵宝可梦的生命值
So we've modified the health of the defending Pokemon.
然后在第一个过程之后发生什么 在那个过程完成之后
And then what happens after the first one, after that process is finished.
观众：对另一边重复一遍？
AUDIENCE: Repeat for the other side?
演讲者1：完全正确 重复完全相同的事情 但在另一边
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, repeat the exact same thing, but for the other side.
但我们在这两者之间做了什么呢？
But what are we doing in between each of those?
我们得做点什么
We have to do something.
观众：检查是否有人死亡
AUDIENCE: Checking if somebody dies.
演讲者1：准确地说 检查是否有人死亡
SPEAKER 1: Checking if somebody dies, exactly.
如果有人死了--
And if somebody dies--
假设我们死了 会发生什么？
let's say we die, what happens?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
演讲者1：嗯 我们是的 我们回到播放状态
SPEAKER 1: Well, we yeah, we go back to the play state.
我们淡出到黑色 然后我们回到播放状态
We fade out to black, and then we go back to the play state.
如果我们消灭敌人会发生什么？
What happens if we knock out the enemy?
观众：转到这个屏幕
AUDIENCE: Go to this screen.
演讲者1：没错 这个屏幕上会发生什么？
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, and what happens on this screen?
那么 第一件发生的事情是什么？
So what's the first thing that happens?
那么 回想一下 精灵宝可梦死的时候发生了什么？
Well, so recall, what happened when the Pokemon died?
发生了什么？
What happened?
观众：它从站台上掉了下来
AUDIENCE: It fell off its platform thing.
演讲者1：没错 所以这可能是他的y值的一个区间
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, so that's a tween probably, right, on his y value.
然后会发生什么呢？
Then what happens?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
演讲者1：没错 我们把一个战斗信息状态推到了屏幕上
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, we've pushed a battle message state onto the screen.
然后当我们按Enter键时会发生什么？
And then what happens when we press Enter?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
演讲者1：刚才发生了什么？
SPEAKER 1: What just happened right there?
观众：[听不见]文本框上写着
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] text box that says,
你得到了所有的经验点
you earned whatever experience points.
然后你的XP就会升级
Then you get your XP goes up.
大概 它会检查你是否升级了
And presumably, it checks if you leveled up.
演讲者1：是的 正确
SPEAKER 1: Yes, correct.
观众：[听不见]调高音量
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] to level up.
演讲者1：完全正确 所以当推动对话时
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, so when push a dialogue
在屏幕上显示你获得了x个经验点 XP酒吧的青少年
to the screen that says you've earned x experience points, the XP bar tweens,
对吗？
right?
我们已经达到了当前XP与下一级XP的比率
We've gone up to however our ratio of current XP to next level XP is.
我们以这种方式制作文本栏动画 或以这种方式制作进度条
We animate our text bar that way, or progress bar that way.
然后我们把州内的淡入淡出 对 变成白色
Then we push a fade in state, right, to white.
然后我们必须把所有东西都从堆栈中取出
And then we have to pop everything off the stack,
然后将淡出状态推送到堆栈的顶部
and then push a fade out state to the top of the stack,
然后我们又回到了游戏状态
and then we're back to the play state.
但如果我们真的升级了 我们需要播放正确的音乐 播放正确的声音
But if we do level up, we need to play the right music, play the right sound,
然后赋值的一部分实际上是 在那个确切的函数中
and then part of the assignment will be actually, in that exact function,
你需要添加一些行为来做什么？
you're going to need to add some behavior that will do what?
观众：[听不见]基本上是显示变化
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] display the change basically,
以及新的一个将会是什么
and what the new one will be.
演讲者1：是的 我们需要做些什么呢？
SPEAKER 1: Yes, and what are we going to need to do.
我们需要做什么才能做到这一点？
What will we need to do in order to?
观众：[？解释 ？]它叫什么来着？
AUDIENCE: [? Explain, ?] what was it called?
选择框 但基本没有选择部分
The selection box, but without the selection part basically.
演讲者1：是的 所以一旦我们采取了--一旦我们升级了
SPEAKER 1: Yes, so once we've taken-- once we've leveled up
我们处于战斗状态的胜利状态 对吧
and we're in that victory state of the battle state, right,
我们需要推送一个新状态 一个新的菜单状态
we need to push a new state, a new menu state, which
拥有所有这些统计数据以及它们增加的数量
has all of those stats and the amount that they've increased.
然后当我们按回车键时 大概我们
And then when we press Enter, presumably, we
应该把它弹出来 然后把其他的都弹回播放状态
should pop that off, and then pop everything else back to the play state,
然后像往常一样淡入
and then do the fade in as normal.
简而言之 这就是战斗状态
And that is the battle state in a nutshell,
很多东西都在等待着彼此的输入和其他东西
a lot of pieces that sort of are waiting on each other and input and stuff
就像那样
like that.
但相当容易理解 只是因为它的许多内容非常简单
But fairly easy to understand, just because a lot of it is very simple
只是一遍又一遍地链接在一起的东西
things that are just chained together over and over
再次产生这种有趣的行为
again to produce this sort of interesting behavior.
所以我们这里有精灵 回想一下精灵是什么
So here we have sprites, recall the sprites are what
我们需要对它们进行动画处理
we're going to need to animate those.
我们有健康条 也就是进度条
We have health bars, which are progress bars, which
就是两个长方形--
are just two rectangles that are--
一条线 一条黑线 和一条填充在线下的填充
ones a line, a black line, and ones a fill that fills beneath the line,
这样我们就能知道少了多少 对吧？
so that we get a sense of how much is missing, right?
我们得到了宽度、高度和颜色
We get the width, the height, a color.
我们可以给进度条添加任何我们想要的颜色
We can give our progress bar any color we want to,
这就是我们如何区分健康吧和XP
which is how we get the difference between, say, a health bar and an XP
酒吧
bar.
我们只画一个红色和一个蓝色 然后把它们画在不同的地方 对吧
We just make one red and one blue, and we draw them in different spots, right,
但它们都是进步的标杆
but they're both equally progress bars.
然后他们就会得到一个价值
And then they get a value.
它们的值决定了矩形的大小
Their value is whatever sort of determines how much of the rectangle
是按比例调整的
is scaled.
最大值就是应该按顺序除以多少
And the max is how much that should be divided by in order
以求出总宽度的比率--
to produce a ratio for the total width--
一个总宽度的定标器 这将允许我们
a scaler for the total width, which will allow us
以获得丢失的数量的感觉
to get the sense of an amount missing.
然后一个球员圈x 对手圈
And then a player circle x, opponent circle
X代表省略号 只是实际口袋妖怪的图形细节
x for the ellipses, just the graphical details for the actual Pokemon,
这样我们就可以得到他们的数据 这样我们就可以真正地掷骰子 或者不掷骰子
so that we can get their stats, so that we can actually do dice rolls, or not
在这种情况下确实掷骰子 但这样我们就可以加或减
really dice rolls in this case, but so that we can add or subtract
惠普以进攻和防守为基础
HP based on attack and defense.
这就是最新的情况 所以把扳机滑进去
And so here was the update, so trigger slide in.
因此 触发滑动所做的是一秒钟的补间
So what trigger slide in does, is a one second tween,
你说过的 对吧？
which you talked about, right?
精灵宝可梦从左到右 或者从左到右 从右到左
The Pokemon going left to right, or left to right, right to left.
有x个值 只需一秒钟就可以补齐
There x values, just tweening in over one second.
一旦完成 我们将触发开始对话
As soon as that's finished, we're going to trigger starting dialogue.
因此 开始对话是将战斗消息状态推送到堆栈上
So the starting dialogue is push a battle message state onto the stack.
战斗消息状态类似于对话状态 因为它获取一个字符串
The battle message state is just like a dialogue state in that it gets a string
在这里 一个狂野的东西出现了
here, so a wild something appears.
一旦我们按回车键 它就会得到一个回调函数
It gets a callback function for once we press Enter on that.
回调函数本身就是战斗消息状态的又一次推送
And the callback function is itself another push of a battle message state
上面写着 去吧 然后是我们的精灵宝可梦
that says, go, and then our Pokemon.
请注意 我们在这里引用的是self.opcient.party.pokemon
So notice that we're referencing the self.opponent.party.pokemon there,
在那里使用self.player.party.pokemon来获取实际名称
and self.player.party.pokemon there to get the actual name.
然后一旦我们弹出 然后我们在这里按下战斗菜单状态
And then once we've popped that off, then we push a battle menu state here,
对吗？
right?
那么 让我们来看看战斗菜单状态
So let's take a look at the battle menu state.
这很有趣 因为这就是我们真正定义的
So this is interesting, because this is where we actually define
我们菜单的行为是有效的 对吗？
the behavior for our menu works, right?
回想一下 我们需要一些东西来告诉我们当我们按下Fight时会发生什么
Recall, we need something to tells us what happens when we press Fight,
以及当我们单击Run时会发生什么
and what happens when we click Run.
因此 当我们点击Fight时 请注意此处的项目
So when we click Fight, notice here items,
对 self.warflemenu获得菜单 并且菜单需要项目
right, self.battlemenu gets menu, and menu expects items.
这项关键字 这张桌子直接输入到选择中 对吗？
This items key, this table gets fed right into the selection, right?
和选择 它希望记住 一篇文字
And the selection, it expects remember, a text,
因为它必须知道在该索引处呈现什么
because it has to know what to render at that index.
然后是ON SELECT功能
And then an on select function.
而On SELECT函数是回调
And that on select function is the callback
当您在该特定位置按Enter键时执行的
that gets executed when you press Enter at that particular location
在菜单上
in the menu.
在这种情况下 战斗 它所做的是弹出这个战斗菜单状态
In this case, fight, what that does is it pops this battle menu state where
我们不再需要菜单了 打开它吧
we no longer need the menu, so pop it.
然后推动一个新的转弯状态
And then push a new take turn state.
然后在这个游戏中轮流状态是精灵宝可梦相互战斗 那就是
And then take turn state in this game is the Pokemon fighting each other, that's
转弯状态是什么
what the take turn state is.
例如 它可以被称为战斗状态
And it could have been called fight state, for example,
但Take Turn State的用途更多一点
but take turn state is a little more versatile.
如果我们想制造一个精灵宝可梦想要运行
If we wanted to maybe make, maybe one Pokemon wants to run,
敌人想跑 我们想打 对吧？
the enemy wants to run and we want to fight, right?
但你不能总是跑 所以他们应该试着跑
But you can't always run, so they should try to run,
然后我们仍然可以和他们战斗
and then we can still fight them.
或者他们可以使用物品 或者我们可以使用物品 对吗？
Or they can use an item, or we can use an item, right?
你可以做很多不同的事情
There's a lot of different things you can do.
或者我们想向他们扔一个弹子球 如果我们失败了
Or we want to throw a Poke ball at them, and if we fail,
那他们就应该和我们战斗 对吗？
then they should fight us, right?
轮流只是一种通用状态
Take turn is just a general purpose state
我们可以改变用途 无论我们有什么用途
that we could repurpose for whatever use we
想要与我们和对手之间的任何互动
want to with any interaction between us and the opponent,
无论是打架 逃跑 还是使用物品 抓住他们 任何
whether it's fighting, running away, or using items, catching them, any
这些东西的组合
of these combinations of things.
但在这种情况下 为了这个例子 为了简单起见
But in this case, for the sake of this example, for simplicity,
我们只实施了战斗
we've only implemented fighting.
我们和对手在这种状态下相互战斗 这是
The we and the opponent fight each other during this state, which
一人攻击另一人 然后我们检查死亡人数
is, one attacks the other, and then we check for deaths
介于两者之间
in between both of those.
然后走向胜利或伪装取决于哪一种是正确的
And then go to victory or feinting depending on which of those holds true,
如果有的话
if either.
跑步则略有不同
Running is slightly different.
因此 如果我们运行 我已经将其编程为100% 它将100%地工作
So if we run, I've programmed it to be 100%, it will 100% of the time work.
在精灵宝可梦中 你实际上有机会运行
In Pokemon, you actually have a chance to run
根据你和你的敌人之间的三角洲
based on what the delta is between you and your enemy.
因此 如果他们比你强大 你实际上并不能保证会逃走
So if they're stronger than you, you actually aren't guaranteed to run away.
所以我们在我的实现中所做的是 我们只是弹出战斗菜单
So what we do here in my implementation is, we just pop the battle menu,
所以它不见了
so it's gone.
然后我们推 你成功逃到了屏幕上 这就是战斗信息
And then we push, you fled successfully to the screen, this battle message.
但这与我们展示的其他战斗信息有所不同
But there's a difference here versus the other battle messages that we've shown.
我的意思是 这并不是真的不同 但这是值得记住的事情
I mean, it's not really different, but it's something to keep in mind.
所以我要投入一场战斗
So I'm going to get into a battle.
首先 通过你刚才在屏幕上看到的信息
And so first of all, with that message that you just saw on the screen,
我必须真的按回车键 对吗？
I had to actually press Enter, right?
我通过按Enter键显式删除了它
I discarded it explicitly by pressing Enter.
对于这些信息来说也是如此
And that holds true also for these messages.
在我按Enter键之前 它什么都不会做
It won't do anything until I press Enter.
所以我按Enter键 然后我按Enter键 它就这样做了
So I press Enter, and then I press Enter, and it does it's thing.
但请注意当我点击Run时的不同
But notice the difference between when I hit Run.
我要按下Run 我逃走了 它会自己跑的
I'm going to hit Run, I fled, and it does it on its own.
它不是在等待输入 对吧？
It's not waiting for input, right?
那么我们是如何实现这一点的呢？
So how have we implemented that?
嗯?
Yeah?
观众：使用定时器 你会自动
AUDIENCE: Using timer, you'd automatically
像之后那样做 而不是等待您的输入
do it the same way you would afterwards, instead of waiting for you input,
您只需等待计时器结束
you just wait for the timer to end.
演讲者1：没错 所以我们使用计时器 然后当计时器结束时
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, so we use a timer, and then when the timer is finished,
我们弹出战斗信息 就像我们按回车键弹出它一样
we pop the battle message just like we would have popped it by pressing Enter.
这面假旗让我们可以这么做
This false flag is what allows us to do that.
我们按假和假是 我们可以输入或不？
We press false and false is, can we input or not?
但我们不能
And we can't.
所以实际上 如果我们在这之后不做任何计时器的事情
So actually, if we didn't do any timer thing after this,
我们刚刚做了一个假旗 战斗信息将永远存在
and we just did that false flag, the battle message would be there forever,
我们永远也摆脱不了
and we could never get rid of it, ever.
它会永远卡住
It would get stuck forever.
所以我们要负责任地说 好吧 我们要放一个计时器
So we got to be responsible and say, OK, we're going to put a timer,
我们将在0.5秒后立即调用timer
we're going to call timer.after 0.5 seconds immediately after that.
我们要在州内推行一种淡化
We're going to push a fade in state.
然后我们要做这两个弹出操作 一旦它消失了
And then we're going to do these two pop operations here as soon as that fade in
发生了
happens.
第一次弹出会弹出一条信息 对吧 这条信息
This first pop will pop the message, right, this message here
我们没有通过输入弹出
that we didn't pop through input.
所以这实际上是垃圾收集 在某种意义上 对我们来说
So this is actually garbage collecting, in a sense, for us.
它丢弃了我们不能自动丢弃的信息
It's discarding the message that we couldn't discard automatically.
然后我们要进入战斗状态 对吧
And then we're going to pop the battle state, right?
所以跑步会推送战斗信息 触发一个补间计时器
So running will push the battle message, trigger a timer tween
我们的计时器 五秒钟后 对不起 按下淡入状态
for our timer.after five seconds, sorry, push a fade in state.
然后在状态淡出完成后 弹出这两个状态
And then after the fade in states done, then pop both of those states.
消息和战斗状态将我们带回到游戏状态
The message and the battle state take us back to the play state.
一切结束后我们就去那里
And that's where we'll be as soon as that's all done.
这就是战斗菜单状态中的所有内容
And that's all that's in the battle menu state.
任何问题 以如何战斗菜单工程 战斗之间的区别
Any questions as to how the battle menu works, the difference between fight
以及它们是如何运作的
and run and sort of how those operate?
好的.
OK.
让我们来看看
So let's take a look then at the take turn
国家 这是最后一块 也是最大的一块
state, which is the last piece and the largest piece I would say.
这是与任务最相关的
This is the most relevant to the assignment.
所以我们保持一个参考 口袋妖怪是第一个或第二个去
So we maintain a reference to which Pokemon is first or second to go,
哪个精灵是第一个或第二个 哪个进度条是
which sprite is first or second to go, and which progress bar is
第一个或第二个到这里来
first or second to go up here.
就像我说的 我们这样做是基于速度
And we do that, like I said, based on speed.
所以无论哪个精灵宝可梦更快 我们也可以
So whichever Pokemon is faster, and we could have also
只是通过保持精灵和进步 让这一切变得更短了
made this a little bit shorter, just by keeping the sprites and the progress
BAR作为Pokemon对象或类的成员
bars as members of the Pokemon object, or the class,
但由于他们是分开的 就像我们不一定
but since they're kind of separated, like we don't necessarily
我想让一个口袋妖怪一直引用它的进度条
want a Pokemon to have a reference to it's progress bar at all times,
或者我的意思是 你可以
or I mean, you could.
没有什么能阻止你去做这件事
There's nothing preventing you from doing it.
它只会用来缩短这里的代码
It would only serve the purpose of shortening this code here.
但我们需要保持对此的引用 这样我们才能在这里调用攻击
But we need to keep a reference to this so that we can call attack here,
这是这一大块代码的两次 而不需要
which is this large bit of code twice, without needing
将所有代码复制两次
to duplicate all of that code twice.
这说得通吗？
Does that makes sense?
托尼 你有什么问题吗？
So Tony, did you have a question?
观众：嗯 我只是在想 你也许可以
AUDIENCE: Well, I was just thinking, you could probably
将其放入帮助器函数中 您只需
put that into a helper function where you just
更改您传递它的顺序
change the order you pass it in.
演讲者1：什么？
SPEAKER 1: Sorry?
再说一遍
Say it again.
观众：我只是觉得 我想你可以接受代码
AUDIENCE: I just kind of feel like, I guess you could take the code,
我想 你可以避免重复这一点
and you could avoid duplicating that I guess.
因为它只是颠倒了 所以你可以做的是--
'Cause it's just reversed, so what you could do is you could--
如果你传入一个帮助器函数 你只需要
if you passed into a helper function, which you would just,
而不是先通过它--
instead of passing it first--
对手精灵宝可梦 玩家精灵宝可梦
instead of passing it, opponent Pokemon, player Pokemon,
你会通过它 玩家精灵宝可梦 对手精灵宝可梦
you would pass it, player Pokemon, opponent Pokemon.
我认为这可能会奏效
And that would probably work I think.
演讲者1：好吧 你也要考虑到--
SPEAKER 1: Well, you also have to take into consideration--
所以评论是 你可以传给玩家口袋妖怪和对手
so the comment was, you could pass in the player Pokemon and the opponent
将精灵宝可梦转化为一个函数 然后在该函数中反转它们
Pokemon into a function, and then you reverse them in that function,
我认为 要尊重它们 扭转它们
I'm assuming, have reverence them and reverse them.
但精灵与精灵精灵是分离的
But the sprites are decoupled from the Pokemon,
进度条也与精灵宝可梦分离
and the progress bars are also decoupled from the Pokemon.
所以我们可以通过将这四个东西放在这里来缩短它
So we could shorten this by making these four things here fields
精灵宝可梦对象 但严格来说它们并不是
of the Pokemon objects, but they're not strictly
与精灵宝可梦对象的操作相关
pertinent to the operation of the Pokemon object.
这让精灵宝可梦的物件有点
And it sort of kind of makes the Pokemon objects a little
也 基本上不够抽象或足够轻量级
too, not basically abstract or lightweight enough,
它只是为了达到这一点的目的
and it only serves the purpose of this point,
只需缩短这一小段代码
of just shortening this bit of code.
可能有一种更优雅的方式来做到这一点 但很难说
There's probably a more elegant way to do it, but it's hard to say.
如果这个代码变得更大 也许
If this code were to get larger, maybe.
但其主旨基本上是拥有
But the gist of this is basically to have
指向任何Pokemon、进度条和精灵的指针应该首先操作
a pointer to whatever Pokemon, progress bars, and sprites should operate first
在攻击中 而不是在第二次行动中
in the attack versus what should operate second.
然后 两人将根据谁是第一个 谁是谁的顺序交换拳头
And then the two will trade blows in order based on who's first and who
第二
second.
所以当我们进入转弯状态时 我们是
So when we enter the take turn state, we're
将触发攻击 这里是函数攻击 我们将在
going to trigger that attack, here this function attack, which we'll take in
第一 第二 第一 第二 第一 第二
first, second, first, second, first, second for the Pokemon
雪碧和进度条
sprite and progress bars.
然后是匿名函数 它被执行为
And then anonymous function, which get's executed as
一旦攻击结束 对吗？
soon as the attack is finished, right?
所以这是一个代码 它将弹出一条在攻击中被推送的消息
So this is a code that will pop a message that gets pushed in attack,
然后这就是我们真正检查死亡人数的地方 对吗？
and then this is where we actually check deaths, right?
它将决定我们是走向胜利还是走向黯淡的屏幕
And it will determine whether we go to victory or faint screen or not.
如果不是 如果是 我们就回来
If not, and we return if so.
如果没有 我们将进行另一次攻击 但请看
If not, we're going to do another attack, but see,
现在一切都颠倒过来了
everything is reversed now.
现在是第二 第一 第二 第一 第二 第一
Now it's second, first, second, first, second, first.
所以我们有相同的功能 自我攻击
So we have the same function, self attack,
这只会收留袭击者
which just takes in the attacker.
它实际上是 攻击者 防御者 攻击者 防御者 攻击者
And it's effectively, attacker, defender, attacker, defender, attacker,
精灵精灵和进度条的后卫
defender for the Pokemon sprites and progress bars.
所以这里的攻击函数首先推动一个--
And so the attack function here first pushes a--
好吧 好吧
well, OK.
攻击是什么--
What does the attack--
让我们再复习一遍
let's go over it one more time.
我们认为攻击功能按顺序执行什么操作
What do we think the attack function does in order.
我们刚刚报道了他们 但是什么？
We covered them just a moment ago, but what
当一种东西攻击另一种东西时 发生的顺序是什么？
was the order that happens when something attacks another thing?
嗯?
Yeah?
观众：袭击者呈白色闪烁
AUDIENCE: The attacker blinks white.
扬声器1：攻击者呈白色闪烁
SPEAKER 1: Attacker blinks white.
观众：然后防守者眨眼表示不透明
AUDIENCE: Then the defender blinks opacity.
演讲者1：防御者切换它的不透明度
SPEAKER 1: The defender toggles it's opacity.
观众：健康吧也缩水了
AUDIENCE: And the health bar shrinks.
演讲者1：健康吧缩小了
SPEAKER 1: Health bar shrinks.
没错 然后基本上就是为了进攻了 对吧？
Exactly, and then that's basically it for attack, right?
眨眼 播放声音 眨眼 播放声音 缩小酒吧
Blink, play a sound, blink, play a sound, shrink the bar,
同时 我们也在破坏这一功能
and also we're doing damage in that function as well.
事实上 我们必须改变精灵宝可梦的状态
We actually have to change the status of the Pokemon.
所以这实际上就是它开始的地方 对吗？
So this is effectively where it starts, right?
我们将战斗消息状态放到堆栈上
We place a battle message state onto the stack that says,
攻击者名称攻击防御者名称
the attacker name attacks the defender name.
请注意 它会像Run消息一样变为FALSE
Notice that it gets false just like the run message
是的 因为我们这里不接受输入
did, because we're not accepting input here.
但这实际上取决于我们 它在进入状态的第42行完成
But it's up to us actually, it done up here at line 42 of the enter state.
但我们将在0.5秒后播放攻击动画
But we're going to after 0.5 seconds, play the attack animation.
因此 每0.1秒就启动一次声音
So power up sound every 0.1 second.
我们会记住精灵身上闪烁的旗帜
We're going to member the blinking flag on the sprite,
我们将通过不将其设置为自身来切换它
we're going to toggle it by setting it not to itself.
因此 如果某个东西不是它本身 如果它是真实的价值 它就会变得虚假
So if something is not itself, if it's a truthy value, it becomes falsy,
如果它是假的 它就会变成真的
if it's falsy, it becomes truthy.
所以基本上 在真与假之间来回切换
So basically, toggling between true and false.
限制为六个 对 因为记住 每一份遗嘱
Limit of six, right, because remember, every will
无限期地做某件事
do something every amount of time indefinitely,
除非您传入某个值的限制 在本例中 限制为6
unless you pass in a limit of some value, in this case, a limit of six.
所以我们说 只执行这段代码六次 只眨眼六次 对吧
So we're saying, only execute this code six times, only blink six times, right,
只切换六次 眨眼三次 对吧
only toggle six times, blink three times, right,
因为它必须时断时续
because it has to go on and off.
然后 当这六次迭代完成后
And then as soon as those six iterations are completed,
我们在该Timer对象上调用已完成的函数
we call the finished function on that timer object,
这是一种诚实的行为
which takes an honest function.
一旦发生这种情况 我们就做不透明的部分 对吗？
As soon as that happens, we do the opacity bit, right?
我们对进攻者眨眼 所以现在我们要对防守者眨眼
We blinked the attackers, so now we've got to blink the defender.
所以我们播放热门音乐
So we play the hit sound.
我们做的和刚才对眨眼时做的完全一样 只是现在
We do the exact same thing that we just did for the blinking, only now,
每0.1秒 我们将其不透明度设置为64或255
every 0.1 second, we are setting its opacity to either 64 or 255,
取决于其不透明度的值 对吗？
depending on what the value of its opacity is, right?
所以我们在64到255之间切换
So we are toggling between 64 and 255.
六个极限 取一个函数 计算损害
Limit of six, take a function, calculate damage,
我们刚刚非常简单地做到了 进攻减去防守 对 到1
which we've just very simply done it, attack minus defense, right, up to 1
尽管如此
though.
因此 如果防守实际上高于进攻
So if the defense is actually higher than the attack,
但仍会造成至少一次伤害
which will still do at least one damage.
然后在0.5秒内 我们拿起防守杆
And then over 0.5 seconds, we take the defenders bar,
我们的价值等于他们当前的生命值减去伤害 对吗？
and we tween the value equal to their current HP minus damage, right?
然后它将设置在进度条中 设置它的值
And then that will set in the bar, in the progress bar, it'll set its value.
即使进度条落后于州政府
And even though the progress bar is behind state wise,
对 它在堆栈的底部 因为它处于战斗状态
right, it's on the bottom of the stack, because it's on the battle state.
我们目前正处于转弯状态
And we're in currently the take turn state,
而是因为我们仍在操纵该州的价值观
but because we're still manipulating the values of that state,
我们正在呈现每个州 我们实际上仍然在操纵
and we're rendering every state, we're actually still manipulating
不管它不在堆栈的顶部这一事实 该状态
that state regardless of the fact that it's not on the top of the stack.
所以这允许我们缩小精灵宝可梦进度条 不管它是什么
So that allows us to shrink that Pokemon's progress bar regardless of it
不管是不是在股票的顶端
being on the top of the stock or not.
一旦结束了 一旦结束了
Then once that's finished, once the tween is finished,
实际上将当前的HP设置为该值
actually set the current HP to that amount,
因为我们只调整了进度条的值 即
because we're only tweening the progress bar's value, which is
独立于精灵宝可梦的价值
independent from the Pokemon's value.
然后 攻击就结束了
And then that's the end of the attack.
攻击在这一点上完全结束了
The attack is completely finished at that point.
关于袭击是如何运作的 有什么问题吗？
So any questions as to how the attack works?
基本上就是一串十几岁的孩子
Just a chain of tweens basically.
所以我们进行一次攻击 然后检查死亡人数是下一个功能
So we do an attack, then check deaths is the next function.
我们快结束了 我要快点走了 现在是7：30
And we're almost finished, I'm going to kind of go quickly here, it's at 7:30.
检查死亡是玩家口袋妖怪当前的HP小于等于0
Check deaths is the player Pokemon current HP less and equal to 0,
还是对手精灵宝可梦目前的HP小于等于零
or is the opponent Pokemon current HP less and equal to zero.
如果前者是真的 我们需要晕倒 如果后者是真的
If the former's true, we need to faint, and if the latter is true,
我们需要走向胜利
we need to go to victory.
所以晕倒实际上是一种战斗状态 对 当它说 你晕倒了
So faint is effectively a battle state, right, when it says, you fainted.
然后呢？
And then what?
还记得我们晕倒的时候会发生什么吗？
Remember what happens when we faint?
观众：[听不见]文本框 然后就离开了
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] text box, and then it leaves.
演讲者1：它离开了 你还记得怎么走吗？
SPEAKER 1: It leaves, do you remember how
例如 它离开是因为它与逃跑不同？
it leaves as it differs from like running away, for example?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
演讲者1：嗯 除此之外 从美学上讲
SPEAKER 1: Well, beyond that, aesthetically,
你还记得有什么不同吗？
do you remember how it's different?
观众：(听不见)我认为 这和黑人不同
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] differently to black, I think.
演讲者1：的确如此
SPEAKER 1: It does.
相反 它会褪色为黑色
It fades to black instead.
所以这就是我们在晕倒时如何区分
So that's how we can differentiate when we're fainting
而不是我们逃跑的时候
versus when we're running away.
这就是我们在这里做的事情
And so that's what we're doing here.
请注意 状态RGB中的淡入度为零 所有这些
Notice that the fade in state RGB is zero, all of those.
因此 它将淡入到000255 而不是255255,255,255
So it's going to fade in to 000255, as opposed to 255, 255, 255, 255.
所以这将是一个黑色淡入与白色淡入
So it's going to be a black fade in versus a white fade in.
然后一旦我们--
And then once we've--
这只是我实现的一种方式
this it just sort of a thing that I implemented so
我们可以无限期地继续比赛
that we can keep playing indefinitely.
但一旦完成 让玩家口袋妖怪完全恢复健康
But once that's finished, restore the player Pokemon to full health,
恢复所有现场音乐的内容
resume all the field music stuff.
一旦我们推入淡出状态 000
And then once we've pushed a fade out state, 000,
然后我们又回到了赛场 让我们继续前进
and then we've gone back to the field, let's push.
注意 这里它接受一个函数 在淡出状态完成之后
Notice that here it takes a function, right, after the fade out state's done.
一旦淡出完成--所以只要我们回到播放状态
Once the fade out is finished-- so as soon as we're back to the play state,
按下对话状态 上面写着：您的精灵宝可梦
push a dialogue state that says, your Pokemon
已完全恢复 请重试
has been fully restored, try again.
这将根据上下文 我们将[INAUDIBLE]
Which will take the context, and we'll [INAUDIBLE]
按Enter键跳过它
to press Enter to get past it.
那是在晕倒
That's fainting.
胜利稍微更有活力一些
Victory is a little bit more robust.
所以胜利就是--你还记得当我们取得胜利时会发生什么吗？
So victory is-- do you remember what happen when we get a victory?
观众：嗯 它还得检查调平
AUDIENCE: Well, it has to check leveling up as well.
它说 你已经击败了你的对手 然后你的XP条增加了
It says, you've defeated your opponent, then your XP bar increases.
如果你升级了 它会告诉你你升级了
Then if you've leveled up, it tells you that you leveled up,
然后它就离开了
and then it leaves.
演讲者1：它告诉你你打败了你的对手 XP条增加了
SPEAKER 1: So it tells you you defeated your opponent, XP bar increases,
检查上一级 然后离开
checks for a level up, and then leaves.
在显示或不显示升级消息后 它离开
After displaying the level up message or not, it leaves.
准确地说 它会将所有东西弹回播放状态
It pops everything back to the play state, exactly.
所以请记住 发生的第一件事
So remember, the very first thing that happens
尽管如此 对手精灵在0.2秒的过程中被打了补丁
though, the opponent sprite gets tweened over the course of 0.2 seconds,
它的y值等于虚拟高度 这意味着
it's y value to virtual height, which means,
一直到屏幕的底部 对吗？
all the way to the bottom of the screen, right?
典型的从精灵宝可梦中击败你的对手的动画
The typical defeated your opponent from Pokemon sort of animation.
一旦完成 播放胜利的音乐
Once that's finished, play victory music,
推送一个战斗信息状态 上面写着 胜利 对吗？
push a battle message state that says, victory, right?
一旦它从堆栈中弹出 计算XP
Once that's popped of the stack, calculate the XP,
也就是说 我刚刚选择了任意加和那个精灵宝可梦时代的所有IV
which is, I just chose arbitrarily sum all the IVs of that Pokemon times
它是Level 这就是你得到的XP
it's level, and that's the XP you got.
推送一个状态 上面写着 你赢得了xXP 对吗？
Push a state that says, you earned x XP, right?
它是假的 所以这意味着它不接受输入
It's false, so that means it doesn't take input.
因此 这意味着这取决于我们 以便将其从堆栈中弹出
So that means it's up to us in order to pop that off the stack.
所以1.5秒后 我们播放一段声音 然后我们在XP栏向上移动
So after 1.5 seconds, we play a sound, and then we tween that XP bar going up,
对吗？
right?
这就是发生在这里的事情 self.bustleState.playerxpbar
So that's what's going on here, self.battleState.playerxpbar,
我们正在调整数学 人 XP和XP的人
we're tweening of the math.men, of the XP plus XP,
或者XP升级 因为如果我们不这样做 它可能会越过XP条的边缘
or XP to level, because if we don't, it could go past the edge of the XP bar,
因为我们可以把我们的经验提升到一个水平 对吗？
because we could go over our XP to level, right?
假设我们有10个经验值 直到我们达到一个等级 我们可以获得20个经验值
Let's say we have 10 XP till we gain a level, we could gain 20 XP.
我们会落入10XP的圈套
We'd be 10 XP overboard.
因此 我们不想在XP栏的边缘之外补间XP栏
So we don't want to tween our XP bar past the edge of the XP bar,
这将是一个图形故障
it would be a graphical glitch.
所以算一算 我们的XP加上XP 我们的XP达到了水平
So a math.men our XP plus XP, and our XP to level,
它将取两个值中较小的一个
which will take the lesser of the two values.
一旦完成 它被补齐 我们将弹出消息
Once that's done, it's tweened, we're going to pop the message off,
然后我们将实际添加XP 级别更高
and then we're going to actually add the XP, level up.
因此 如果XP大于XP to Level 这就是我们升级的地方
So this is where we level up if the XP is greater than XP to level.
播放声音 将XP设置为当前XP减去2级XP
Play a sound, set the XP to the current XP minus our 2 level XP,
这意味着我们会有一些结转 对吗？
which will mean that we'll have some carry over, right?
然后实际调用Level Up函数
And then actually call the level up function.
这就是--
Now here is where--
哦 还有 在那之后 祝贺你 你升级了
oh, and also after that, congratulations, you've leveled up.
淡出白色 这只是一个白色淡出这里
Fadeout white, which is just a white fade out here.
我用了两次 所以我为它做了一个函数
I used it twice, so I made a function for it.
只是在状态中推动淡入淡出
Just pushes a fade in state.
停止胜利的音乐 播放田野音乐 流行 推入淡出状态
Stop the victory music, play the field music, pop, push a fade out state.
所以不管怎样 当我们取得胜利时 我们会把淡出的颜色变成白色
So either way, when we've got a victory, we're going to push a fade out white,
或者我们会把淡出称为白色 对吗？
or we're going to call fade out white, correct?
所以推送战斗信息状态 然后尽快
So push a battle message state, and then as soon
当我们按回车键时 因为我们升级了 淡出为白色
as we press Enter, because we leveled up, fade out to white.
如果我们没有升级 但我们还是取得了胜利
And if we didn't level up, but we still got to victory,
我们仍然需要淡出白色
we still need to fade out white.
这就是你们的作业 作业7
And so this is where your assignment is, assignment 7.
作业7是 注意我们已经升级了self.playerPokemon级别
Assignments 7 is, notice that we have self.playerPokemon level up.
我们需要在这里做的关键事情是
The key thing that we are going to need to do here
就是添加一个菜单 显示我们是如何升级的
is add a menu that shows us how we leveled up.
如果您还记得 playerPokemon Level Up会返回所有统计数据
And if you recall, playerPokemon level up returns all the stats
你已经提升了这个级别
that you've increased this level.
所以你可以显示一个菜单 上面只写着 你的惠普加那个金额 对吗？
So you can show a menu that just says, your HP plus that amount, right?
您将获得所有四个值
You're going to get all four values.
它将爆炸式增长到所有这四个值
It's going to explode to all four of those values.
然后你将创造一场新的战斗--
And then you're going to create a new battle--
或者不是新的战斗菜单 而是你想要的任何新菜单
or not new battle menu, but a new menu of whatever you want,
但可能在物品垂直高度的右侧
but probably on the right side of some vertical height for items.
这里唯一的区别 唯一的关键
The only difference here, the only key thing
你将会考虑到
that you're going to take into consideration
是 我会回到幻灯片 因为我们实际上
is, and I'll go back to the slides, because we're actually
在这一点上完成了代码的检查
done at this point going over the code.
但是选择项 你实际上不能选择任何东西
But the selection items, you won't be able to actually select anything,
这将是纯粹的视觉效果
it's just going to be purely visual.
因此 您需要编辑所选内容才能选择
So you're going to need to edit selection to have the option
没有光标
to not have a cursor.
这一点在规范中有详细说明 实际上
And this is detailed in the spec, which was actually
在今天的讲座前发布
released before lecture today.
所以你可以看看这个
So you can take a look at that.
但您需要对选择进行更改
But you'll need to make a change to selection.
但所有的碎片都在那里
But all the pieces are there.
这应该是一项相当容易的任务 只要
It should be a fairly easy assignment as long
当你了解这些州是如何运作的 菜单是如何运作的
as you understand how the states work, how the menu works,
以及如何基于这些值创建菜单
and how to create a menu based on those values,
以及如何从Level Up中实际获取值
and how to actually get the values from level up.
因此 一些我们没有讨论的、我们没有实现的缺失功能
So some missing features that we didn't talk about, which we didn't implement
例如 屏幕的详细程度
are, for example, the detailed level of screen,
抓怪兽是你的任务 对吧？
which is your assignment, monster catching, right?
在整个过程中我们只有一个精灵宝可梦的派对
We only have a party of one Pokemon throughout this whole entire thing,
但可以说 这项运动的主要吸引力之一是能够捕捉到更多
but one of the arguably main appeals of the game is to be able to catch more.
所以这将是一些需要添加的东西 需要对可能添加到游戏中的内容进行优先排序
So that would be something to add, to prioritize probably adding to the game.
一个现场菜单 可以真正看到你捕捉到的所有精灵宝可梦
A field menu so can actually look at all the Pokemon you've caught.
这会很好 这样你就可以真正看到他们有多少惠普
That would be nice, so you can actually see how much HP they have.
在物品库存中 因为游戏 常规游戏中都有物品
In item inventory, because the game, the regular games have items.
你可以使用魔药 你可以找到金块
You can use potions, you can find gold nuggets
你卖了一大笔钱
that you sell for a ton of money.
不同的能力 目前我们基本上只有一次战斗行动
Different abilities, currently we only have basically one fight operation,
这就像是铲球
which is like a tackle.
而游戏本身 常规的游戏也有
And the game itself, the regular game has
就像100多个具有基本属性的不同动作一样
like over 100 different moves that have elemental attributes,
做不同的事情 造成地位的影响
and do different things, and cause status effects,
提高你或你的对手的威力
buff you or your opponent.
所以加入这些是很有吸引力的 也许是
So adding those is appealing, and maybe being
能够将它们表示为适合的数据
able to represent them as data is nice to.
你可以在游戏中遇到的训练者 他们有自己的预设
Trainers that you can encounter in the game that have their own preset
或者随机化的精灵宝可梦去战斗
or randomized Pokemon for to fight.
怪物进化 因为这是最有趣的事情之一
Monster evolution, because that's like one of the funnest things
是拿着一个非常虚弱的精灵宝可梦 就像提高
is taking a really weak Pokemon, and like raising
它变得非常强大 并在一定程度上进化
it to become really strong, and evolving it at a certain level.
城镇 路线 其他水平 不仅仅是我们的基本正方形区域
Towns, routes, other levels beyond just our basic square area.
怪物繁殖 在第二季中介绍
Monster breeding, which is introduced in the second series,
这样你就可以拿到两个精灵宝可梦
so that you can take two Pokemon and have a chance
为了得到一个拥有非常好的统计数据的鸡蛋或者一个非常稀有的精灵宝可梦
to get an egg with really good stats or a really rare Pokemon from it.
然后就像一个昼夜循环 也许就是不同的精灵宝可梦出现的地方
And then like a day night cycle maybe where different Pokemon come out
在一天中的不同时间
at different times of the day.
所以你被激励在不同时间打球
So you are incentivize to play at different times
就是为了这个目的
of the day for that purpose.
但精灵宝可梦就到此为止了
But that was it for Pokemon.
下周 我们将真正深入到“团结”中去
Next week we'll actually be diving into Unity.
所以我们实际上已经完成了爱情2D 这是非常有趣的
So we're actually done with LOVE 2D, which is a lot of fun,
但现在我们将探讨如何制作3D游戏
but now we'll be going into how to make 3D games.
这是我们下周将制作的游戏的截图
So this is a screenshot from the game we'll be making next week,
这是一种3D侧滚Flappy Bird风格的直升机
which is a 3D sort of side scrolling Flappy Bird esque helicopter
这款游戏是根据著名的网络游戏《直升机游戏》改编的
game based on a famous web game called Helicopter Game.
它可以说是Flappy Bird的早期祖先之一
And it was sort of one of the early ancestors to Flappy Bird.
在维基百科的页面上 实际上也是这样说的
On the Wikipedia page, it actually says that too.
我记得打球 那是在2007年 或者2006年 或者类似的事情
I remember playing, it was back in like 2007, or 2006, or something like that.
但你在这个游戏中的目标--这是一个修改后的版本--
But your goal in this game-- this is a modified version of that--
你的目标是你的--一切都是3D的 但它是一个侧面滚动的视角
your goal is your-- everything is 3D, but it's a side scrolling perspective.
因此 这被称为2.5D 因为这个原因
So this is called 2.5D for that reason.
你控制着一架直升机 你就是那架紫色直升机
You're controlling a helicopter, you're the purple helicopter.
你的目标是在一个无限滚动的世界里
And your goal is to in an infinitely scrolling world.
因此 我们将重温无限滚动 但在3D中 请避开摩天大楼
So we'll revisit infinite scrolling, but in 3D, avoid skyscrapers.
所以你可以看到那里有一座绿色的摩天大楼 造型简陋
So you can see there is a green skyscraper, crudely modeled.
收集硬币 你可以看到那里有一枚硬币 这是一枚3D硬币
Collect coins, so you can see there's a coin there, it's a 3D coin,
它将永远在旋转
it will always be spinning.
你的硬币在右上角
Your coins are up at the top right.
你会看到一个无限滚动的背景
You'll see a background that's infinitely scrolling.
然后你会有随机的喷气式飞机
And then you'll have jets that will randomly
在你上方飞翔 给你另一种层次或维度
fly above you to sort of give you another sort of layer or dimension
需要注意的障碍
of obstacles to watch out for.
这将教会我们很多关于团结是如何运作的基础知识
And this will teach us a lot of the basics of how unity works,
所以我们可以开始进入更有趣的事情 比如第一人称
so we can start getting into even more interesting things like a first person
就像是核心探险游戏
like sort of core exploration game.
最后 当我们在门户网站的学期结束时
And then lastly, when we end the semester with Portal,
我们将在那里看几件奇特的东西
we'll look at a couple of fancy things there.
但精灵宝可梦就到此为止了
But that was it for Pokemon.
感谢你们的光临 我们下次再见
Thanks for coming, and I'll see you guys next
时间到了
time.